good night everyone
おやすみなさい、皆さん
speech is about to start
スピーチが始まろうとしています
Please set your phone to vibrate or elite
携帯電話を振動またはエリートに設定してください
speech in progress
スピーチ中
Do not take photos with flash
フラッシュを使用して写真を撮らないでください
Thank you for your cooperation
ご協力ありがとうございます
Ladies and gentlemen, hello everyone
皆様、こんにちは。
I am the deputy executive secretary of the Academic Advisory Council of Academia Sinica
私は中央研究院学術諮問委員会の副事務局長です。
My name is Li Chaohuang
私の名前は李朝黄です
So the poster was supposed to say
だからポスターはこう言うはずだった
Today is hosted by Vice President Zhou Meiyin
今日は周美音副総統が司会を務める
But I'm sorry because the vice president
でも副社長だからごめんなさい
Temporarily have this overseas itinerary
一時的にこの海外旅程を保持する
there is no way to get back
戻る方法はありません
So today I will help him host
だから今日は彼のホストを手伝います
Then if you become a fan of Vice President Zhou again
それでまた周副総統のファンになったら
first say sorry
まずごめんなさいと言う
so thank you all very much tonight
それでは皆さん、今夜は本当にありがとうございました
Use this time after school to attend
放課後のこの時間を利用して参加してください
our show
私たちのショー
Feast of Knowledge held by the Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine
中医病院主催の知識の饗宴
Well, we have held this event many times
さて、このイベントは何度も開催していますが、
Also accumulated a lot of interesting this
これも面白いものがたくさん集まりました
Some articles on popular science
ポピュラーサイエンスに関するいくつかの記事
Well, there are books outside our collection of articles from previous knowledge feasts
さて、以前の知識の饗宴からの記事のコレクション以外にも本があります
So if you are interested, you can also buy it
興味があれば購入することもできますので、
Well, what we are talking about today is actually quite a life-like technology.
さて、私たちが今日話していることは、実際には非常に現実的なテクノロジーです。
Although it has a lot of basic research elements in it
基礎研究的な要素が多く含まれていますが、
But the title is a word I think everyone has heard of Thermoelectric Technology
しかし、タイトルは熱電技術について誰もが聞いたことがある言葉だと思います
That is simply how to convert heat into electricity
それは単純に熱を電気に変換する方法です
Because we know a lot of this energy
私たちはこのエネルギーの多くを知っているので、
It's used then last because the efficiency is not 100%
効率が100%ではないため、最後に使用されます。
So in the end it's all in the form of waste heat
結局のところ、それはすべて廃熱の形になります
into our rooms or into the atmosphere
私たちの部屋や大気中に
or drain into the water
または水に流す
Then these heats are okay
じゃあこの暑さは大丈夫だよ
energy used
使用されるエネルギー
But, the problem is that it's not easy to collect
しかし、問題は集めにくいことです
because it's going to be like all kinds of
あらゆる種類のことになるから
That is to say, from high temperature to low temperature to diverge
つまり、高温から低温へ分岐します。
So the development of thermoelectric technology is in
そこで、熱電技術の開発が進んでいます。
How can we improve energy efficiency now
今すぐエネルギー効率を改善するにはどうすればよいですか
how to improve the earth
地球をどう改善するか
Energy consumption is a very, very
エネルギーの消費は非常に多く、
Issues in the spotlight
注目を集めている問題
Then we are very honored to have this today
それでは、本日は大変光栄に存じます
Our Institute of Atomic and Molecular Sciences, Academia Sinica
中央研究院原子分子科学研究所
Director Chen Guixian is here to introduce this
陳桂仙監督がご紹介します
very important technology
非常に重要な技術
Then let me briefly introduce Director Chen Guixian
それでは、陳桂先監督を簡単に紹介させていただきます
In fact, I've known him for probably over 20 years.
実際、私はおそらく20年以上彼を知っています。
I don't know if there are 30 years
30年あるかどうかは分からない
That's definitely over 20 years
間違いなく20年以上経つよ
Director Chen is
チェン監督は、
Graduated from the Department of Electrical Engineering, National Taiwan University in 1970
1970年国立台湾大学電気工学科卒業
That
それか
The BA of the big TV drama should have started a business at that time
あの頃大ドラマのBAは起業すべきだった
It's right to be a tech upstart
テクノロジーの新興企業になるのは正しいことだ
However, Director Chen, because of his interest in science
しかし、チェン監督は科学に興味があったため、
so he went to harvard
それで彼はハーバード大学に行きました
Then earned a Ph.D. in 1989
その後1989年に博士号を取得
Then he did this
それから彼はこれをしました
Doing this man-made diamond research at that singular company
その特異な会社で人工ダイヤモンドの研究を行っている
Should be very promising
非常に有望なはずです
I don't know why he changed his career again
なぜ彼がまた転職したのか分かりません
Director Chen is obviously quite persistent in academics
陳所長は明らかに学問に非常に固執している
Then in 1993 he returned to China to serve
その後、1993年に中国に戻り、奉仕した。
joined the Institute of Atomic and Molecular Sciences
原子分子科学研究所に入所
The way from this research assistant to
この研究助手から
Bitcoin researcher Na is also the director
ビットコイン研究者のナ氏もディレクターを務める
So based on what I know of him
私が彼について知っていることに基づくと、
I think Director Chen is one
チェン監督もその一人だと思います
a scientist forever
永遠の科学者
because when i knew him
なぜなら私が彼を知ったとき
he is still very young
彼はまだとても若いです
very dark hair
とても黒い髪
Since then we have seen
それ以来、私たちは見てきました
At that time we will call him Mr. Chen
その時は彼をチェンさんと呼ぶことにします
He just has always been able to offer his unique perspective on a variety of issues
彼は常にさまざまな問題について独自の視点を提供することができました
And keep producing this very creative
そして、この非常にクリエイティブなものを生み出し続けてください
And there are groundbreaking research results
そして画期的な研究結果も出ています
Then I think in an environment like Academia Sinica
それなら中央研究院のような環境で考えます
It is a place that complements such good scientists
そんな優れた科学者を補完する場所です
We see how good scientists grow
優秀な科学者がどのように成長していくのかがわかります
Then we see good scientists like this
そうすると、このような優れた科学者が現れます
Why did you go back and contribute to Academia Sinica?
なぜ戻って中央研究院に貢献したのですか？
Director Chen is a very, very successful example
チェン監督は非常に成功した例です
OK, then I'll introduce it here
はい、それではここで紹介させていただきます
Then we will hand over the time to Mr. Chen Gui, the director
その後、ディレクターのチェン・グイ氏に時間を渡します。
please applaud everyone thank you
みなさん拍手してください、ありがとう
ok thank you host for this
わかりました、ホストに感謝します
flatter me
お世辞でもうれしいわ
i think everyone knows
誰もが知っていると思います
He is special in several institutes
彼はいくつかの研究機関で特別な研究を行っています
We have the original institute, the mathematics institute and the astronomy institute
私たちは独自の研究所、数学研究所、天文学研究所を持っています。
It's on the campus of National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学のキャンパス内にあります
So this has
それで、これは
Although I often come back to the courtyard for meetings
打ち合わせで中庭に戻ることも多いのですが、
But it's my first time to speak here
でも、ここで話すのは初めてです
The one that the host didn't introduce just now
今ホストが紹介しなかったもの
In addition to graduating from the Department of Electrical Engineering, I went to the United States to study
電気工学科卒業と同時に渡米。
I think the more exciting part of life
人生のもっとエキサイティングな部分だと思う
It was the years when I came back
戻ってきた年でした
At that time, our Taiwan happened to be from that
その時、私たちの台湾はたまたまそこから来ました
at the time of national transition
国家移行期に
There used to be only three TVs
昔はテレビが3台しかなかった
Then there are only seven newspapers
そうなると新聞は7社しかない
no more
もういや
Then we have been going everywhere to demand that the party and government
それから私たちは党と政府に要求するためにどこへでも行きました。
have your own voice, your own what
自分の声、自分のものを持ってください
Why was there a so-called underground radio station for a while?
なぜ一時期いわゆる地下ラジオ局があったのでしょうか？
get it up from the ground
地面から引き上げる
There are several home appliances in Taiwan now
台湾には現在いくつかの家電製品があります
The radio station was founded by me
そのラジオ局は私によって設立されました
And then also in public television
そして公共テレビでも
Including Hakka TV
客家テレビを含む
But this is all related to today's theme
しかし、これはすべて今日のテーマに関係しています
Today's topic is
今日のトピックは
What I'm going to tell you today is thermoelectric technology
今日私がお話しするのは、熱電技術です。
heat into electricity or electricity into heat
熱を電気に、または電気を熱に
Turning electricity into heat is easy, right?
電気を熱に変えるのは簡単ですよね？
Let's pass the current through any light bulb
電球に電流を流してみましょう
Cook it hot
調理すると熱くなります
But it turns electricity into heat
でも電気を熱に変えるんだよ
It can also convert electricity into energy
電気をエネルギーに変換することもできます
wait a minute i can introduce you
ちょっと待ってください、紹介できます
It's more difficult to get things down
物事を落ち着かせるのはさらに難しい
English it is called
英語ではこう呼ばれます
It's a direct flip with this thermoelectric
この熱電素子を使ったダイレクトフリップです
Then I want to tell you today
それから今日言いたいのは
from some of its applications
いくつかのアプリケーションから
it can be taken from the refrigerator at home
自宅の冷蔵庫から取り出せる
communication even to space
宇宙まで通信可能
Some history of these past developments
これらの過去の開発の歴史
the whole outline for today
今日の全体概要
right from the beginning of it
最初からすぐに
Motivation
モチベーション
how did it start
どのようにして始まりましたか
and then from its past development history
そして過去の開発履歴から
And then what we're going to bump into is to discuss
そして、私たちがぶつかろうとしているのは、議論することです
That is to say, what kind of difficulties did it encounter?
つまり、どのような困難に遭遇したのでしょうか？
what chance
何のチャンスだ
how to solve the difficulty
困難を解決する方法
Everyone is still working hard
みんなまだまだ頑張ってるよ
then to the conclusion
それから結論へ
This was the beginning of everyone's idea
これがみんなのアイデアの始まりでした
just want to say
ただ言いたいだけです
we are in many
私たちはたくさんの中にいます
We are called ICE
私たちはICEと呼ばれています
internal combustion engine
内燃エンジン
After the Industrial Revolution, machines replaced ordinary animals or humans
産業革命後、機械は普通の動物や人間に取って代わりました
The most important thing about the machine is that it never cares whether you are burning coal
この機械について最も重要なことは、石炭を燃やしているかどうかを気にしないことです。
Either burn oil or burn natural gas
石油を燃やすか天然ガスを燃やすか
You call these oil charcoal or Fast or Fuel
あなたはこれらの油を炭または高速または燃料と呼びます
These fossils that we live under the ground
私たちが地下に住んでいるこれらの化石
Fast or Fuel should be translated like this
Fast または Fuel は次のように翻訳する必要があります
You burn it to generate heat
燃やすと熱が発生します
Then after it is hot, it pushes the engine of the machine
そして熱くなってから機械のエンジンを押します。
But if you review it
でも見直してみると
You will find that a lot of heat is generated after you burn
燃焼後はかなりの熱が発生することがわかります。
But maybe only 25% 30% are actually used to do what you want to do
でも、実際にやりたいことに使われるのは 25% ～ 30% だけかもしれません
most of that
そのほとんどが
More than 60 percent of the heat in this part is wasted
この部分の熱の 60 パーセント以上が無駄になります
It's hard for everyone to imagine
誰もが想像するのは難しい
say you drive a car
車を運転すると言う
or drive a motorcycle
またはバイクを運転する
Actually all the same
実は全部同じ
look at that car
あの車を見てください
car it doesn't just say
車、ただ言うだけではありません
it moves it smokes
それは動きます、それは煙を吐きます
You need one more in your car
車にもう1台必要です
we call cooling water
私たちは冷却水を冷却水と呼びます
our radiate
私たちの放射
what is our chinese name
私たちの中国名は何ですか
three
三個
radiate is not
放射ではありません
radiate is
放射するのは
We have a cooled front of the car
車の前部は冷却されています
cooling
冷却
water fragrance
水の香り
water fragrance is
水の香りは
Then why the perfume
ではなぜ香水なのか
it's your eyes that are too hot
熱すぎるのはあなたの目です
so you have to cool it with water
だから水で冷やす必要がある
since you are hot
あなたは暑いから
why do you want to water it
なぜ水をやりたいのですか
cool it down drain it
冷まして水気を切ります
isn't this a waste
これは無駄ではないですか
In fact it means
実際、それは意味します
After our gasoline goes to burn
ガソリンが燃えた後
Mostly more than 60%
ほとんどが60％以上
is scattered
散らばっている
Only 30% of them help us work
私たちの仕事を手伝ってくれる人はそのうちの 30% だけです
the engine is running
エンジンは動いています
so what
だから何
If we understand such a situation in the future
今後このような状況が理解できた場合
someone wants to say
誰かが言いたい
Wow, this one is still 60% hot
うわー、これはまだ 60% 熱いです
let's make good use of it
上手に活用しましょう
then i remember when i was young
それから私は若い頃のことを思い出します
Sitting on the mountain in Nantou
南投の山の上に座って
they have that iron bullock cart
彼らはその鉄の牛車を持っています
drive very slowly
非常にゆっくり運転する
Iron ox carts also burn oil
鉄牛車も油を燃やす
see you diesel or something
またディーゼルか何か
that water
その水
Cool water burns hot
冷たい水は熱く燃えます
So people will be in the cooling water
それで人々は冷却水の中にいるでしょう
put some eggs in there
そこに卵をいくつか入れます
then at noon
それから正午に
only eggs to eat
食べるのは卵だけ
that might be a
それはかもしれない
Flying fish hot for reuse
再利用可能なトビウオ
After all, it is limited
やっぱり限界があるんだね
Most of the heat is still dissipated
熱の大部分はまだ放散されています
so what
だから何
Many people wanted to say
多くの人が言いたかった
If I take this heat and find a way to recycle it
この熱をリサイクルする方法を見つけられたら
That
それか
Suppose you are sixty percent
あなたが60パーセントだとしましょう
It would be nice if my efficiency was even 10 percent
効率が10パーセントでもあればいいのですが
Then I can recycle 6% back
そうすれば 6% をリサイクルできます
that's a lot
それは多いです
so what
だから何
a lot of research
たくさんの研究
that's just right
それはちょうどいいです
thermoelectric
熱電
because it's hot
暑いから
right
右
If this heat is converted into electricity
この熱を電気に変えれば
that would be perfect
それは完璧でしょう
So it's not really a new topic
だからそれは実際には新しい話題ではない
for example
例えば
This German BMW
このドイツBMW
we are bmw
私たちはBMWです
they used to do
彼らはかつてやっていた
that is
あれは
thermoelectric material
熱電材料
put it on the face of this engine
このエンジンの前面に付けてください
or that exhaust pipe
あるいはその排気管
exhaust pipe is hot
排気管が熱い
look at that motorcycle
あのバイクを見てください
The exhaust pipes have to be covered.
排気管はカバーする必要があります。
you accidentally get burned
うっかり火傷を負ってしまう
You take this thermoelectric material
あなたはこの熱電材料を手に取ります
stick it on
貼ってください
it's ok
大丈夫です
Save about 5% to 10% on gasoline
ガソリン代が約5%～10%節約できます
General Motors GM of America
ゼネラルモーターズアメリカGM
It also added a 350 watt thermoelectric system later
後に 350 ワットの熱電システムも追加されました
it found that
それはわかった
The mileage of this car can be increased by 3%-4%
この車の走行距離は 3% ～ 4% 伸びる可能性があります
That
それか
Although
それでも
3%-4% or this saves 5%-10%
3% ～ 4%、またはこれにより 5% ～ 10% 節約されます
sounds small
小さく聞こえる
But what if you say
しかし、あなたが言ったらどうしますか
This every car we
これはすべての車に私たちが
The world produces tens of millions of cars every year
世界では毎年数千万台の自動車が生産されています
Save this on every car
これをすべての車に保存します
In fact, it is still very impressive
実際、それは今でも非常に印象的です
That
それか
Then we have to ask why there is no such thing in the cars we buy today.
それでは、なぜ今日購入する車にこの機能が搭載されていないのかを尋ねる必要があります。
we will come
我々は来ます
Let's discuss
話し合いましょう
That's because such a
そんなことだから
this thought
この考え
we are at
私たちは〜にて
A hospital of traditional Chinese medicine started a called
伝統的な中国医学の病院が電話を開始しました
Thermoelectric Research Program
熱電研究プログラム
what about this plan
この計画はどうですか
from
から
Fate
運命
and the Institute of Physics
そして物理学研究所
Fate Institute, except that I am the general convener
運命研究所、ただし私が総招集者であることを除いて
Our current deputy chief Wei Jinming
現在の副部長魏錦明
turn out to be
であった
This one is Vice President Zhou Meiyin
この人は副総統の周美音です
After becoming the vice president
副社長就任後
I just want to say that I don't want to ask for a referee
ただ言いたいのは、審判を求めたくないということです
So he hastened to give
それで彼は急いで与えました
a young
若者
Wei Jinming
魏錦明
our current deputy chief
私たちの現在の副部長
in the physics institute
物理学研究所で
have
もつ
Chen Yangyuan
チェン・ヤンユアン
Also former Deputy Chief
元副署長も
Dr. Chen Yangyuan
チェン・ヤンユアン博士
And Dr. Wu Maokun
そしてウー・マオクン博士
Academician Wu Maokun
学術研究員 呉茂坤
There is another one who is our Indian nationality
私たちのインド国籍の人がもう一人います
called Sankar
サンカールと呼ばれる
Infection
感染
sorry
ごめん
That
それか
Speaking of
といえば
Dr. Chen Yangyuan, of course, everyone should
チェン・ヤンユアン博士、もちろん誰もがそうすべきです
He's no stranger, he's more senior than me
彼は見知らぬ人ではなく、私よりも先輩です
About ten years ago, I started to do research on thermoelectricity
10年ほど前から熱電の研究を始めました。
It's also because of him that I dare to say
あえて言えるのは彼のせいでもある
Alright then let's get the House team together
さて、それでは下院チームを集めましょう
Academician Wu Zhaokun, you don’t need my introduction
学者の呉昭君、私の紹介は必要ありません。
He became very famous because of these things in the Ministry of Education a while ago.
彼は少し前に文部省でのこれらのことで非常に有名になりました。
In fact he was before the Ministry of Education, he was actually more famous
実際、彼は文部省の前にいたが、実際には彼のほうが有名だった
Everyone knows this superconductor
誰もが知っているこの超電導体
We have a scientific community, we talk about high-temperature superconductivity
私たちには科学コミュニティがあり、高温超伝導について話します
That is to say, the previous superconductivity had to reach almost this absolute zero.
つまり、これまでの超電導はほぼこの絶対零度に達する必要があったのです。
Ten degrees below absolute zero will produce superconductivity anyway
絶対零度より10度低いと超伝導が起こる
Academician Wu Zhaokun and his teacher Zhu Jinwu
学者の呉昭坤とその教師である朱金武
In the United States, Houston at that time
当時のアメリカ、ヒューストンでは
One material they discovered is called YBCO
彼らが発見した材料の1つはYBCOと呼ばれます
four elements together
4つの要素が一緒に
Then raise the temperature of this superconductor to an absolute temperature of 90 degrees
次に、この超伝導体の温度を絶対温度90度まで上昇させます。
If I remember correctly, I just know
私の記憶が正しければ、知っているだけです
That temperature is higher than the temperature of liquid nitrogen
その温度は液体窒素の温度より高い
That was incredible, a very big breakthrough
それは信じられないほどの、非常に大きな進歩でした
Because in the laboratory, laying eggs is like drinking boiled water
実験室で卵を産むのは沸騰したお湯を飲むようなものだから
That is to say, it is actually possible to obtain
つまり、実際に入手できるのは、
Meaning you cool it below the temperature of a fetal egg
胎児の卵の温度以下に冷却することを意味します
superconductivity can be achieved, and a lot of research can be done
超電導が実現でき、多くの研究が可能になる
Can save a lot of energy
多くのエネルギーを節約できます
So Wu Maohui Academy is his contribution
So Wu Maohui Academy は彼の貢献です
his understanding of the material
彼の内容に対する理解
This experience provides a very important support for our team
この経験は私たちのチームに非常に重要なサポートを提供します
In addition to this, Professor Zhou Fangzheng of National Taiwan University Lingtai Center is a Crystal Grower
これに加えて、国立台湾大学霊台センターの周方正教授はクリスタルの栽培者でもあります。
Many thermoelectric materials rely on gold
多くの熱電材料は金に依存しています
Professor Zhang Zhiwei is very experienced in the analysis of a structure of Nimi and his heat conduction telecommunications
Zhang Zhiwei 教授は、ニミの構造解析と熱伝導通信に豊富な経験を持っています。
In the end, Xie Wenbin from the Institute of Earth Sciences started to be a thermal teacher and assistant researcher. He should have given birth recently, right?
結局、地球科学研究所の謝文斌さんは熱学の教師兼研究助手になりましたが、最近出産したはずですよね？
He's been doing really well lately and he's really good at measuring heat conduction.
彼は最近とても調子が良くて、熱伝導の測定がとても得意です。
We formed such a team, of course except for this account
もちろんこのアカウントを除いて、このようなチームを結成しました
In fact, there are many involved behind the scenes
実は裏ではたくさんの人が関わっている
For example, Professor Lin Lixiong present here
たとえば、ここにいる林立雄教授は、
Director of the Front Desk Da Ning Tai Center
フロントデスク ダニンタイセンター ディレクター
also my other half
私の残りの半分も
He's actually been involved in this project all along.
実は彼はずっとこのプロジェクトに関わっていたんです。
Just saying the name doesn't stand here
名前を言うだけではここには入りません
I often say
私はよく言います
I myself was born to learn electrical engineering
私自身、電気工学を学ぶために生まれてきました。
So it is clearer about electricity
電気についてもっとわかりやすくなります
familiar with light
光に詳しい
But when it comes to materials
しかし、材料に関して言えば、
When you come across the structure of this material
この物質の構造を知ると
you put it up
あなたがそれを上げました
you turn it
あなたがそれを回します
what is its symmetry
その対称性は何ですか
get this done
これをやり遂げる
I usually just get dizzy
普段はめまいがするだけです
But luckily when I get sleepy
でも幸運なことに、眠くなったら
I give it to my wife
妻にあげます
She can help me out soon
彼女はすぐに私を助けてくれる
say how it should be
どうあるべきかを言う
So although her name is not posted here
したがって、彼女の名前はここには掲載されていませんが、
I especially acknowledge her
私は特に彼女を認めます
Okay, let's go back to what thermoelectricity is. Simply put, you have a heat, and then, in the process of heat dissipation, it will generate electricity at the same time.
さて、熱電とは何かに戻りますが、簡単に言うと、熱があり、熱が放散される過程で同時に電気が発生します。
As for this thing, about two hundred years ago, this Sebeck discovered such a phenomenon.
これについては、約二百年前に、このセベックがそのような現象を発見しました。
In fact, if you look at his original picture, he found that when he put a metal material through one end and heated it, the heat will flow to the other end.
実際、彼の元の絵を見ると、金属素材を一方の端に通して加熱すると、熱がもう一方の端に流れることがわかりました。
At the same time, he found out that he put one, which is similar to a pointer, the pointer is here, and found that the pointer can move, and then felt very, very...
同時に、彼は針のような針を入れたこと、その針がここにあること、そしてその針が動くことができることを知り、とてもとても...と感じました。
Very surprised
とても驚いた
Then he thought
そこで彼は考えた
This magnetic field is caused by heat
この磁場は熱によって引き起こされます
creates a magnetic field
磁場を作り出す
Not long after that it was confirmed that
それから間もなくして、次のことが確認されました。
In fact, his original idea was wrong.
実際、彼の当初の考えは間違っていました。
It's because after the heat flow
熱が流れた後だから
He will also drive a current
彼はまた、電流を駆動するでしょう
We know this current
私たちはこの流れを知っています
Electricity and magnetism are closely related
電気と磁気は密接な関係にあります
because of current
現在のせいで
So the generated magnetic field deflects the pointer
発生した磁場が針を偏向させます
so what
だから何
We call this thing C-Back Effect
これをCバック効果と呼びます
discovered 200 years ago
200年前に発見された
Then such an Effect
するとこんなエフェクトが
In fact if you are a material
実際、あなたが素材なら
it can also
それもできます
But why do we often draw two
しかし、なぜ私たちはよく2つを描くのでしょうか
We'll tell you later
後ほどお知らせします
Why do they usually come in pairs?
なぜ彼らは通常ペアで来るのですか？
It will be more efficient
より効率的になります
then say another
それから別のことを言う
After the discovery of the thermoelectric effect
熱電効果の発見後
it's been ten years
10年経ちました
Another French scientist named Patel
パテルという名前の別のフランス人科学者
he found out
彼は見つけた
If I am in certain materials
特定のマテリアルの中にいる場合
After I turned it on
電源を入れた後
he found out
彼は見つけた
one end can get very hot
片方の端が非常に熱くなることがあります
even
平
one end can get very cold
片方の端が非常に冷たくなることがあります
it's upside down
これは逆さまです
that is
あれは
Because of the cold temperature difference
寒暖差のせいで
T degree difference so generate electricity
T度差があるので発電する
what about here
ここはどうですか
he means
彼が意味するのは
If I use current
現在を使用する場合
Make a voltage to make it generate a current
電圧をかけて電流を発生させる
One end of the material found to be hot
素材の一端が熱くなっていることが判明
the other end will get cold
向こう側は冷たくなります
At first
初めに
these discoveries
これらの発見
caused a lot
多くのことを引き起こした
everyone's attention
大家的注意
Research
研究
So what about this thing?
それで、これについてはどうですか？
In our general textbooks, there are
私たちの一般的な教科書には、
Wait until later this is called Tomson
後でこれをトムソンと呼ぶまで待ってください
This William Thompson he just came to know about it
このウィリアム・トンプソン、彼は今それについて知りました
In fact, these two things are two sides of the same coin.
実際、これら 2 つは同じコインの表裏の関係にあります。
It's the same thing upside down
上下逆にしても同じことだよ
I have T degrees of temperature and I can generate electricity
気温は T 度で、発電できます
Upside down I push it back with electricity
逆さにして電気で押し戻す
Electricity pushes it back and I can generate heat
電気がそれを押し返して熱を発生させることができます
or a difference in temperature
または温度差
is the same thing
同じことです
It even takes the two coefficients
2 つの係数も必要です
It is CBF and PADF
CBFとPADFです
Association between two coefficients
2 つの係数間の関連性
express it mathematically
それを数学的に表現する
that is a very important contribution
それは非常に重要な貢献です
Then this William Thompson
それからこのウィリアム・トンプソン
He was later dubbed the British
彼は後にブリティッシュと呼ばれるようになった
Lore Kevin
ロア・ケビン
I'm curious about this
これについて興味があります
Strange, his name is Thompson
奇妙なことに、彼の名前はトンプソンです
Then why is it called Kevin
ではなぜケビンと呼ばれるのか
Everyone knows Lore
誰もがロアを知っています
In England they have this class of different nobility
イギリスにはさまざまな貴族階級がいます
some what sir
何か、先生
some monkey prince or something
猿の王子か何か
Then he was named Lore Kevin
その後、彼はロア・ケビンと名付けられました
should have made a great contribution
多大な貢献をしたはずだ
Then why is it called Kevin
ではなぜケビンと呼ばれるのか
If I were Lore Thompson
もし私がロア・トンプソンだったら
Why Lore Kevin
なぜロア・ケビンなのか
In fact
実際には
I think his contribution
彼の貢献だと思います
Another contribution is even greater
もう一つの貢献はさらに大きい
He pushed it down and said
彼はそれを押し下げて言った
have a temperature
体温がある
called the absolute temperature absolute zero
絶対温度を絶対零度と言います
Wow, this is actually today
わあ、実は今日なんです
It is not easy for ordinary guests to think about this
一般のゲストにはなかなか考えられないことです
the idea we know
私たちが知っているアイデア
All objects have a certain temperature
すべての物体には一定の温度があります
Touch our heads, do you have a fever today?
私たちの頭を触ってください、今日は熱がありますか？
Or this cold snap is coming, it's cold outside
それとも、この寒波が来ているので、外は寒いです
Slowly humans figured out and said
人類は徐々に理解して言った
With the concept of temperature, there can be heat
温度の概念があれば熱が存在する可能性がある
Right? Well, then what?
そうだね?それではどうする?
There is a scientist who should be from Denmark or Sweden
デンマークかスウェーデン出身のはずの科学者がいます
Called Selces
セルセスと呼ばれる
He put the water
彼は水を入れた
The freezing temperature is the same as the boiling temperature of water
氷点下は水の沸騰温度と同じです
Eight hundred and one hundred grid
八百百グリッド
hundredths
100分の1
that is our facility today
それが今日の私たちの施設です
Facility temperature
施設温度
I remember going to
に行ったのを覚えています
when denmark
デンマークのとき
there is one
ここに一つ
it was a museum
それは博物館でした
still in front of a train station
まだ駅前にある
Huanong has a very large thermometer
華農は非常に大きな温度計を持っています
Then there is DoC not DoF
次に、DoF ではなく DoC があります
that's why
それが理由です
he just wants
彼はただ欲しいだけです
Xiu said you have a look
シウは「見てください」と言いました
This Sales is someone from their country
このセールスは彼らの国の出身者です
That
それか
Originally set the temperature
もともと設定されていた温度
Use a few degrees C facility a few degrees
数℃の施設を使用する
Then turn this temperature into 100 divisions
次に、この温度を 100 分割します。
really full
本当にいっぱい
Everyone is using it everyday
みんな毎日使ってるよ
but
しかし
from that facility
その施設から
to what we call absolute temperature
私たちが絶対温度と呼ぶものに
this is not easy
これは簡単ではありません
But it's not easy
しかしそれは簡単ではありません
that is
あれは
If we take a
を置くと
material or even biological activity
物質的活動、あるいは生物学的活動さえも
I don't know that no one knew or understood him back then
当時は誰も彼のことを知らず、理解していなかったのかわかりません
When he got this Tomson
彼がこのトムソンを手に入れたとき
That is to say, you put a certain
つまり、特定のものを入れます
Look at the vibration of atoms or what kind of
原子の振動などを見てください。
He transformed this activity into a coordinate with temperature
彼はこの活動を温度との調和に変換しました。
Then this activity becomes smaller and smaller
そうなると、この活動はどんどん小さくなっていきます
If you push to a certain activity when it is as small as 0
特定のアクティビティが 0 のときにプッシュすると、
He found out that the temperature was -273.16 degrees
彼は気温が-273.16度であることを知りました
From that time onwards
その時から
There is a temperature called absolute zero
絶対零度という温度がある
at that temperature
その温度で
all things will stand still
すべてのものが静止するだろう
All creatures are lifeless
すべての生き物は生命を持たない
All objects stop when they are at absolute latitude
すべての天体は絶対緯度にあると停止します
OK
OK
so from this
それではこれから
it got this calvin
それはカルビンを手に入れました
is the absolute temperature
は絶対温度です
That's why it was knighted
だからこそナイトに叙せられたんだよ
Law, didn't I say Law is called Jazz?
ロー、ローのことをジャズと呼んでいるって言いませんでしたか？
It's a knighthood, okay?
それは騎士団です、いいですか？
this is really important
これは本当に重要です
Although it is not directly related to today's hot spots
今日のホットスポットとは直接関係ありませんが、
That absolute temperature
その絶対温度
You seem to say fate
運命って言ってるようだ
What about Fate, we have four groups
Fate はどうですか、グループは 4 つあります
One of them is called AMO
そのうちの 1 つは AMO と呼ばれます
Atomic Molecular and Optics
原子分子と光学
What about this group?
このグループはどうですか？
have a very special plan
非常に特別な計画がある
that is
あれは
This atom or molecule, has been cooling energy
この原子または分子は、エネルギーを冷却しています
How cold can it be?
どれくらい寒いでしょうか？
You said absolute temperature, absolute zero
絶対温度、絶対零度って言ったよね
In fact, no one has ever reached absolute zero.
実際、絶対零度に到達した人は誰もいません。
it's hard
それは難しい
That's all right, then use various methods to cool it under liquid nitrogen
それはそれでいいので、液体窒素でさまざまな方法で冷却します。
liquid liquid nitrogen, and even colder, liquid hydrogen
液体液体窒素、そしてさらに冷たい液体水素
not enough, colder, liquid helium
足りない、冷たい、液体ヘリウム
Liquid helium depends on which kind of helium
液体ヘリウムはヘリウムの種類によって異なります
It's two or three degrees below absolute temperature
絶対温度より 2 ～ 3 度低いです
ok , not cold enough
わかった、まだ寒くないよ
There is a Nobel laureate named Zhu Liwen
朱立文というノーベル賞受賞者がいる
He just uses a laser
彼はレーザーを使っているだけです
Take this atomic molecule and make it move smaller and smaller
この原子分子を​​どんどん小さく動かしてみよう
then reached a few
それからいくつかに達しました
Our name is Milly Kevin
私たちの名前はミリー・ケビンです
minus 3 degrees absolute temperature
絶対温度マイナス3度
wow smaller
すごい小さい
But actually that is not enough
しかし実際にはそれだけでは十分ではありません
early in science
科学の初期の頃
Derivation There is a thing called Bose Einstein
派生ボーズ・アインシュタインというものがある
Condensation Einstein
凝縮アインシュタイン
everyone knows
みんな知ってる
Another one is from India
もう一人はインドから来た
Scientists call Bose VOSE
科学者たちはボーズをVOSEと呼んでいます
They theoretically deduce that
彼らは理論的にそれを推測します
you take this substance
あなたはこの物質を入れます
to a certain extent
ある程度まで
it becomes another state
別の状態になる
we just know
私たちはただ知っています
A substance is either a gas or a liquid
物質は気体か液体のいずれかです
otherwise solid state
それ以外の場合は固体状態
but he said no
しかし彼はノーと言った
At that point it was called Bose Einstein
当時はボーズ・アインシュタインと呼ばれていました
The Condensation is another completely
凝縮はまったく別のものです
status no one has seen
誰も見たことのないステータス
Theoretical derivation
理論的導出
Seventy or eighty years later
70年か80年後
It was proved experimentally that
これは実験的に証明されました
really called BEC
本当にBECと呼ばれます
This Bose Einstein Matter Exists
このボース・アインシュタイン物質は存在する
that's a hot topic
それは熱い話題です
so what
だから何
This BEC
このBEC
just close to
すぐ近くにある
For example, rich six
たとえば、リッチ6
called Microkevin
マイクロケビンと呼ばれる
Now the laboratory can do
今、研究室でできることは、
Nano-Calvin is even lower
ナノカルビンはさらに低い
It's very, very close to absolute zero.
それは絶対零度に非常に近いです。
so what
だから何
This conception of light from temperature
温度による光の概念
to absolute temperature
絶対温度まで
That's what we just talked about
それが今話したことです
you can approach
近づくことができます
How close to absolute zero
絶対零度にどれだけ近づくか
What about this matter?
この件についてはどうですか？
actually
実際
is in what we call
私たちが呼んでいるものにあります
Cold science, it is very cold
風邪の科学、とても寒いです
How to do this very very cold low temperature
この非常に寒い低温をどうやって行うか
ok then we come back
わかりました、それでは戻ります
So, this Tomson has made great contributions
さて、このトムソンは多大な貢献をしました
As for thermoelectricity, he combined two phenomena
熱電に関しては、彼は 2 つの現象を組み合わせました。
string it up
紐を付けて
We call this thermoelectric material two sides of one body
この熱電材料を 1 つの体の 2 つの側面と呼びます。
In fact, we will introduce two phenomena in a moment.
実際に、すぐに 2 つの現象を紹介します。
it all works
それはすべてうまくいきます
Well, I didn't introduce this to you
まあ、これは紹介していませんでしたが、
A man named Gustav Magnus
グスタフ・マグナスという男
It is to combine materials, different materials
素材、異素材を組み合わせる事です
do some experiments like
のようないくつかの実験をしてください
In the end, it turns out that what we call
結局のところ、私たちが呼んでいるものは、
thermocouple
熱偶, thermocouple
We are often in the laboratory, in some laboratories that do physics
私たちはしばしば実験室、物理学を扱ういくつかの研究室にいます。
you want a high temperature
高い体温が欲しいのですか
this one thousand degrees
この1000度
Some are four Baidu
一部は 4 つの百度です
then you have some zero degrees
そうすると、ゼロ度がいくつかあります
200 degrees, how to measure these temperatures
200度、この温度の測り方
The most common is to use two different metals
最も一般的なのは、2 つの異なる金属を使用することです
then chain it together
それからそれを連鎖させます
it will get a potential difference
潜在的な差が出るだろう
That potential difference is related to its temperature
その電位差は温度に関係しています
So, that thing
それで、そのこと
This phenomenon is actually related to the material
この現象は実は材質に関係しています。
its nature is related
その性質は関係している
good
良い
come again, this one
また来てね、これ
called Yof
ヨフと呼ばれる
what about yofy , he ' s a soviet
ヨフィはどうですか、彼はソビエト人です
What about him
彼についてはどうですか
around 1900
1900年頃
he just said
彼はちょうど言った
use a pair
ペアを使用する
First, he uses semiconductor
まず、彼は半導体を使用します
Two sides use a pair, we call P type and N type
両側がペアで使用され、P タイプと N タイプと呼ばれます
Inside, on the semiconductor surface, there are some positive charges on it.
半導体表面の内部では、一部が正電荷を帯びています
There is a kind of charge that replaces more negative charges
より多くのマイナス電荷を置き換える一種の電荷があります
He said, put two times and two times in pairs
彼は言い​​ました、2回と2回をペアにしてください
it can get the highest efficiency
最高の効率を得ることができます
This is also very important, so you see
これも非常に重要なので、わかりますか
the soviet stamp
ソ連の切手
This is 1980, and that was the Soviet Union
これは 1980 年、当時はソ連でした
Soviet Union stamps, there it is
ソ連の切手、あります
That's not the only way, if everyone goes
それが唯一の方法ではない、もしみんなが行けば
That St. Petersburg, let me see, raise your hand if you have been to Russia
サンクトペテルブルク、ロシアに行ったことがある人は手を挙げてください
Many people should have been there, Russia
多くの人がそこにいたはずです、ロシア
doesn't he? no, don't be so polite
いいえ、あまり礼儀正しくしないでください
Have you ever been to St. Petersburg? Raise your hand
サンクトペテルブルクに行ったことがありますか?手を挙げてください
How many have been
何人になりましたか
you went to st petersburg again
またサンクトペテルブルクに行ったんですね
Of course you went to see that so-and-so, that so-and-so East Palace in Kaiserling, right?
もちろん、カイザーリンクの、あの、あの、あの東宮殿を見に行きましたよね？
wow that's beautiful isn't it
うわー、それは美しいですね
What about St. Petersburg?
サンクトペテルブルクはどうですか？
The most important scientific research unit
最も重要な科学研究部門
It's called YORF Institute
YORF研究所といいます
is to commemorate it with its name
その名前で記念することです
then it's on the thermoelectric
それからそれは熱電にあります
it says on the first side it says
最初の面にそう書いてある
This semiconductor is better than this metal material
この半導体はこの金属材料よりも優れています
or other materials or insulating materials
または他の材料または絶縁材料
Suitable
適合
this is very important
これはとても重要です
second it says
二番目にそれは言う
The material is the best
素材は最高です
have a pair
ペアを持っています
One is P-type material
1 つは P タイプの材料です
The other one is N-type material
もう1つはN型材料です
One is a positively charged material
1つは正に帯電した物質です
One is a negatively charged material
1つはマイナスに帯電した物質です
make it paired later
後でペアリングする
everyone can watch
誰もが見ることができます
its electricity
その電気
It can run like this
このように実行できます
So electricity is connected in series
つまり電気は直列に接続されているのです
two things in series
シリーズの2つのこと
strung together these two are strung together
これら 2 つは一緒につながっています
but it's hot
でも暑いです
hot here is hot
ここは暑いです、暑いです
here is can
ここに缶があります
heat is electricity
熱は電気です
This is very strange, our...
これはとても奇妙なことです、私たちは...
It is not easy for you to think that there is a structure that can make heat and electricity
熱や電気を生み出す構造があるとはなかなか考えられません。
let one be in series, one patient
1 人をシリーズにして、1 人の患者を
Then if it is changed in this way, its efficiency can reach the highest
このように変更すると、効率が最高に達する可能性があります。
So why do we often have a lot of materials?
では、なぜ多くの資料が必要になるのでしょうか?
Thermoelectric materials wait for everyone to see
熱電材料は誰もが目にするのを待っています
It's all one-on-one
全て一対一です
This thing is at the back
こいつは後ろにあるよ
Let me take a look, okay, let me tell you first
見てみましょう、わかりました、最初に教えてください
Most of the current thermoelectric materials look like this
現在の熱電材料のほとんどは次のようになります。
It looks like this one by one
一つ一つはこんな感じ
Let's call Array, get it up
Array を呼び出して起動しましょう
Well, among them, they are all in pairs, pairs, pairs, pairs
まあ、その中で、彼らはすべてペア、ペア、ペア、ペアです
can achieve the highest efficiency
最高の効率を達成できる
So here I have brought some materials
そこで、いくつかの資料を持ってきました
It's an oil price company called Malo
マロという石油価格会社です
Take a look and let you pass it on
見てください、そしてそれを伝えましょう
What does this material look like?
この素材はどのように見えますか?
OK
OK
Just look at it and get a feeling
ただ見て、感じてください
What about this material?
この素材はどうでしょうか？
Around the 1940s and 1950s
1940年代から1950年代頃
Very
非常地
Then it became very popular
そしたら大人気になりました
whether it is the soviet union
ソビエト連邦かどうか
Regardless of the United States, etc. are actively researching
アメリカ等でも盛んに研究が進められているが
For example, the earliest product
たとえば、最初期の製品
Just a thermoelectric with an oil lamp
オイルランプを備えた単なる熱電装置
light up
点灯する
Then this heat goes to generate electricity
そしてこの熱が発電に使われるのです
This electricity to power a radio
この電気はラジオを動かすためのものです
Your radio uses its power
ラジオは電力を使用します
then i don't have a radio today
それなら今日はラジオがない
I brought this thing for everyone to see
みんなに見てもらうためにこれを持ってきました
this is also a
これもまた
put a candle underneath
下にキャンドルを置きます
In the future, one side of the thermoelectric material will be heated.
将来的には、熱電材料の片面が加熱されるようになるでしょう。
after heating
加熱後
this
これ
You can see the LED lights
LEDライトが見える
that will be bright
それは明るいでしょう
That
それか
Of course everyone will feel very bored, right?
もちろん、誰もがとても退屈に感じるでしょう?
Then you already have candles and you need to light them again
その場合、すでにキャンドルがあり、再度火をつける必要があります。
What do you do with that LED?
そのLEDを使って何をしますか？
right
右
then you are not this
じゃああなたはこれじゃない
what are we going to do
何しようか
Your word is Diago Gipson
あなたの言葉はディアゴ・ギプソンです
Take the monkey to the mountain
猿を山に連れて行こう
what to do
何をすべきか
but
しかし
if one day
ある日なら
You're going to climb a mountain and you're suddenly stuck in the mountain
山に登ろうとしていると、突然山の中に閉じ込められてしまう
Then your mobile phone has been used
それからあなたの携帯電話は使用されました
This is out of power
これは電源が切れています
Then you asked to save him and found that
それからあなたは彼を救ってほしいと頼んで、それを見つけました。
this
これ
No electricity
電気がありません
if there is this
これがあれば
he can save your life
彼はあなたの命を救うことができます
Of course it's more than that. It's just a
もちろんそれ以上です。
An example would be to say
例としては次のようになります。
your simple one
あなたの単純なもの
oil lamp
石油ランプ
How is it possible to generate electricity
どうやって発電することができるのでしょうか
Then wait a minute, this is over, everyone can take a look
それでは、ちょっと待ってください、これは終わりです、みんな見てください
So, at that time
それで、その時は
either the soviet union
ソ連のどちらか
Many people in the United States are concerned about this thermoelectric material
米国の多くの人々がこの熱電材料に懸念を抱いています
have high dreams
高い夢を持つ
What dream? That is to say, if the material efficiency is high
夢とは? つまり材料効率が高ければ
then i don't need that internal combustion engine, i don't need that engine
だったら、その内燃機関は必要ない、そのエンジンも必要ない
That engine though we have it in every car, right?
そのエンジンはどの車にも搭載されていますよね？
That car is noisy, you know that engine
あの車はうるさい、あのエンジンは知ってるだろう
It explodes every time, go push this spin of yours
毎回爆発する あなたのスピンを押してください
If this efficiency is high enough
この効率が十分に高ければ
then you burn it up and heat it up
それからそれを燃やして加熱します
It turns into electricity, no noise, very stable
電気に変わり、ノイズがなく、非常に安定しています
So at that time, many countries were developing this thermal power
当時、多くの国がこの火力発電を開発していました。
I want to say that one day it will really become a mainstream
いつかそれが本当に主流になるだろうと言いたい
Then such an effort lasted until about the 1970s
その後、このような取り組みは 1970 年代頃まで続きました
In the end, I found out that it doesn't seem to be true.
結局、それは真実ではないようだということがわかりました。
Let's take a look at this in 1960 when
1960 年のことを見てみましょう。
The first paper 1954
最初の論文 1954 年
This one is called Gullsmith
これをガルスミスといいます
He used a material called Bismuth Terrarium
彼はビスマステラリウムと呼ばれる素材を使用しました
Is Geochem B
ジオケムBですか
This material is now turned into a commercial thermoelectric material
この材料は現在、商用の熱電材料として開発されています。
is the most widely used
最も広く使用されている
This Gullsmith is number one
このガルスミスはナンバーワンだよ
One cools it with thermoelectric method to cool it
熱電方式で冷却して冷却します
Cool the material down to sub-zero
材料を氷点下まで冷却する
zero degrees is of course a big milestone
もちろんゼロ度は大きなマイルストーンです
So this establishes a milestone
これでマイルストーンが確立されました
Of course Ghost Miss was originally called Chicago
もちろん、ゴーストミスはもともとシカゴと呼ばれていました
Has many contributions to thermoelectricity including writing this book
この本の執筆を含め、熱電に多くの貢献をしている
It doesn't just write a book, it just lists a
ただ本を書くのではなく、ただリストアップするだけです。
Recently, after getting older, it recently moved to Australia
最近、年齢を重ねてオーストラリアに移住しました
It's a very well-known figure in the thermoelectric community
熱電界では非常によく知られた人物です
I've just covered most of the material
ほとんどの内容をカバーしました
Now pass it down for everyone to see, it looks like this
さあ、みんなに見てもらえるように渡します、こんな感じです
Then it depends on your thickness and height
あとは厚みと身長にもよるけど
If you want to generate electricity, the hot and cold
発電したいなら暑いのも寒いのも
There must be a temperature difference
きっと温度差があるんだろうな
The bigger the temperature difference, the better
温度差が大きいほど良い
so what
だから何
If you are too thin
痩せすぎている場合
You can't get it up if you have a temperature difference
温度差があると起きられない
so generally
とても一般的に
it also has a certain distance
それも一定の距離がある
so it can't be made too thin
なのであまり薄くすることはできません
but if you want to cool down
でもクールダウンしたいなら
it will be easier
もっと簡単になるでしょう
cool down
クールダウン
this can be done
これはできる
even do it with thin film
薄膜でもやってみよう
Then everyone can see
そしたらみんなも見れるよ
Then what
じゃあ何
There is another important
もう一つ重要なことがあります
there are two people
二人います
This is Cody and Abel
こちらはコーディとアベルです
where are they
彼らはどこにいる
in the 1960s
1960年代に
he was the first to propose
彼が最初にプロポーズした
用Silicon Germanium
用Silicon Germanium
this fold
この折り目
Folding system or refinement
折り畳みシステムまたは改良
inside the table table
テーブルテーブルの中
It is folded tin sign from carbon series
カーボンシリーズの折りたたみブリキ看板です
If you were tabled when you were a child
子供の頃にテーブルに置かれていたら
it folds the tie
それはネクタイを折ります
get it together
一緒に集めましょう
become a
になる
this alloy
この合金
That
それか
they figured it out
彼らはそれを理解した
This material can be made into a good thermoelectric material
この材料は優れた熱電材料になる可能性があります
Sure enough, the details about Silicon Jumenium
案の定、シリコン・ジュメニウムの詳細
The first one it can go from room temperature of 300 to 1100 degrees K
最初のものは、室温300度から1100度Kまで上昇することができます。
It is stable at very high temperatures
非常に高温でも安定です
The second more important thing is that it has a radioactive element
次に重要なことは、放射性元素が含まれていることです。
called Putonium
プトニウムと呼ばれる
This Putonium it's dangerous
このプトニウムは危険です
After our nuclear power plant produces nuclear power
原子力発電所が原子力発電を行った後
One of its products is this thing
その商品の一つがこれです
That's because of the radioactive elements in this thing
これは放射性元素が含まれているからです
Radiation is still strong
放射線はまだ強いです
So we don't know what to do with the nuclear waste
だから核廃棄物をどうすればいいのか分からない
And look at this half-life of 24,000 years
そして、この 24,000 年の半減期を見てください。
After it was produced, you said it was not good and you left it
作った後、良くないと言って放置した
Just leave it for a long time
長時間放置するだけ
Is it okay? It will be reduced to half after 24,000 years
大丈夫? 24,000年後には半分になる
So why does everyone have such a headache about nuclear waste?
では、なぜ誰もが核廃棄物についてこれほど頭を悩ませているのでしょうか?
But, it doesn't mean that this material is useless
ただし、この素材が役に立たないというわけではありません
it this
それこの
Because it will always release the medium fat and alpha
中脂肪やアルファを必ず放出してくれるので
this particle
この粒子
It will generate a lot of heat when it hits this metal
この金属に当たるとかなりの熱が発生します
Then it puts out the heat of this radioactive element
そして、この放射性元素の熱を消します。
become hot
熱くなります
To provide silicon germanium to do thermoelectricity to generate electricity
シリコンゲルマニウムを提供して熱電を起こして発電する
Then what
じゃあ何
This power supply made in this way
こうして作られたこの電源
Provided a lot of Apollo this pioneer
この先駆者に多くのアポロを提供しました
The Pioneer seems to have exploded during Longe
パイオニアはロング中に爆発したようだ
Then vacuum, Voyager, Galaxia, Jellilie, etc.
次にバキューム、ボイジャー、ギャラクシア、ジェリーなど。
Many, many spaceships all use
非常に多くの宇宙船はすべて
This method means that everyone can see
この方法だと誰でも見ることができます
It's something, it's a Voyager
それは何か、それはボイジャーです
its this spaceship
この宇宙船です
In addition to all kinds of
あらゆる種類に加えて、
Cameras, other than communication equipment
カメラ、通信機器以外
where its power
その力はどこにあるのか
From this one, it's called RTG
ここからRTGと呼ばれます
RadioIsotope, just that Plutonium
RadioIsotope、まさにプルトニウム
It's called the Confidence Element, and then what?
それは「Confidence Element」と呼ばれていますが、それでは何でしょうか?
Somoelectric is Silicon Dominium
ソモエレクトリックはシリコンドミニウムです
and then generate electricity
そして発電します
Then its detailed structure looks like this
その詳細な構造は次のようになります
I don't think I need to explain it to you carefully.
丁寧に説明する必要はないと思います。
That is to say, it basically takes Putonium
つまり、基本的にはプトニウムが必要です
Put this on, it's hot, it's hot
これを着てください、暑いです、暑いです
This element is placed here, and after hitting the surface
この要素はここに配置され、表面に到達した後
it takes heat, puts it here, and pours
熱を奪ってここに置き、注ぐ
Then through thermoelectric materials, and finally
次に熱電材料を経て、最後に
Pass the electricity, this one out
電気を流して、これを消してください
Of course, many people will wonder
もちろん疑問に思う人も多いだろう
Our normal spacecraft don't need this
私たちの通常の宇宙船にはこれは必要ありません
You can use solar panels, right?
ソーラーパネルも使えるんですよね？
while outer space is running
宇宙空間が走っている間
The sun is stronger than the surface of the earth
太陽は地表より強い
then why do you need this
ではなぜこれが必要なのでしょうか
In fact, ordinary spaceships
実は普通の宇宙船は
In fact, it would be better to use solar panels
本当はソーラーパネルを使った方が良いのですが、
But there are many special uses
でも特殊な使い方もたくさんある
Come and see everyone
みんなに会いに来てね
For example, this is the Voyager sailing plus
たとえば、これはボイジャー セーリング プラスです。
it rises from the earth
それは大地から湧き上がる
around 1776
1776年頃
There are two Voyager 1 and Voyager 2
ボイジャー1号とボイジャー2号は2機あります。
two nautical pluses
2つの航海プラス
slippery as it wanders
歩き回ると滑りやすい
Rocket ascends to outer space
ロケットが宇宙へ上昇
and start orbiting the earth
そして地球の周りを回り始めます
centripetal force
求心力
just kept going around there
ただそこを歩き続けた
around to a certain extent
ある程度の範囲で
it gives a little motivation
それは少しモチベーションを与えます
then from the earth
それから地球から
pull this is a
引っ張ってください、これは
Jupiter
木星
to the next planet
次の惑星へ
and go around to it over there
そしてそこに行ってください
All the pictures to be probed have been taken
調査対象の写真はすべて撮影されています
then give it a little more motivation
それからもう少しモチベーションを上げてください
It ran to the next one to Saturn
次の土星へ走りました
even what
たとえ何であっても
Uranus or Minwang
ウラヌスとかミンワンとか
ancestor star
祖先の星
then to Uranus
それから天王星へ
Jupiter goes down one by one
木星が一つずつ沈んでいく
It uses a very clever
とても賢い使い方をしています
a physical method
物理的な方法
use very little energy
エネルギーをほとんど使わない
just use its centrifugal force
遠心力をそのまま利用する
it goes from one to one to one
それは1から1へ1へと進みます
and put the whole sun
そして太陽全体を当ててください
Visit all these stars
これらすべての星を訪れてください
Even I remember when there were several stars with their moons
私でも、月のある星がいくつかあったときのことを覚えています
didn't know before
以前は知らなかった
Because this Voyager went to shoot very clearly
このボイジャーは非常に鮮明に撮影に行ったので、
such a contribution
そのような貢献
Everyone should know that you are on Earth
あなたが地球上にいることを誰もが知っているはずです
you might be on mars
あなたは火星にいるかもしれません
strong sunlight
強い日差し
No problem with solar version
ソーラー版なら問題ない
but
しかし
you are farther away
あなたはもっと遠くにいる
to Saturn
土星へ
to Jupiter
木星へ
too far from the sun
太陽から遠すぎる
not enough sunlight
日光が足りない
Provide the solar energy you want
必要な太陽エネルギーを提供します
so what
だから何
why it needs to be used
なぜそれを使用する必要があるのか
radioactive elements
放射性元素
Then come to provide power
それなら力を与えに来てください
that's how it came
それがこうして来た
then everyone can watch
そしたらみんなも見れるよ
because it is radioactive
放射性物質だから
in the process of claiming
請求手続き中
all
全て
to be in this
この中にいること
All the space suits in this Clean Room have to be worn
このクリーンルームではすべての宇宙服を着用する必要があります
Do you know why? Why is it needed?
なぜそれが必要なのか知っていますか?
Just put it back on
ただ元に戻すだけです
There is no need for the auxiliary line, there is no way to block this
補助線は必要ありません、これをブロックする方法はありません
Auxiliary line, you have to wear Qianyi
補助線、Qianyiを着用する必要があります
why is this? you need to know
これはなぜですか?知っておく必要があります
You go take an X-ray
レントゲンを撮りに行ってください
Tell you how many times I take a photo
何回写真を撮ったか教えてください
how many doses is it right
何回投与するのが正しいですか
Then you said, it’s best not to take more than a few times a year
それからあなたは年に数回以上は取らないほうがいいと言いました
Too many security photos are not good
防犯写真が多すぎるのは良くありません
everybody knows
誰もが知っている
But today if you say
でも今日、こう言うなら
we have a composite
私たちは複合体を持っています
or radial rebar
またはラジアル鉄筋
if one day
ある日なら
you accidentally sucked into your body
誤って体に吸い込まれてしまった
Then the radioactive substance stays in your body
そうなると放射性物質は体内に残ります
It's like an X-ray inside a body
体内のX線写真のようなものです
I've been taking photos with you
あなたと一緒に写真を撮ってきました
then you are very very dangerous
それならあなたはとてもとても危険です
Because if you suck it in, you can't get it out
吸い込むと抜け出せないから
and stay inside you
そしてあなたの中に留まってください
it goes on and on
それはずっと続く
within its half-period
その半期以内に
it just keeps emitting this radiation
この放射線を放出し続けるだけです
so it's very dangerous
だからとても危険です、とても危険です
so what
だから何
Absolutely no radiation pollution
放射能汚染は絶対にありません
Or it's the same when you go to a nuclear power plant
あるいは原子力発電所に行っても同じです。
You can't let radioactive material get into your body
放射性物質を体内に入れてはいけない
good
良い
this is a
これは
this nautical plus spaceship
この航海プラス宇宙船
this person is special
この人は特別です
His name is Ed Stone
彼の名前はエド・ストーンです
He was the host of the project
彼はそのプロジェクトの主催者でした
NASA
NASA
When Launch Voyager
ボイジャー起動時
his host
彼のホスト
that was very successful
それは大成功でした
Everyone can think of AZ
誰もがAZを思いつくでしょう
I just told you
私はちょうどあなたに言いました
Skip from planet to planet Skip from planet to planet
惑星から惑星へスキップ 惑星から惑星へスキップ
Walk all the stars of the sun
太陽の星々を歩いて行こう
Many people will ask him
多くの人が彼に尋ねるだろう
What about going to the last one?
最後まで行くのはどうですか？
Does anyone know
誰か知っていますか
What is the one that went the furthest after the detection?
検出後に最も遠くまで行ったのは何ですか?
star?
星？
after that
その後
No
いいえ
What are the hundreds of millions of planets in the universe afraid of?
宇宙の何億もの惑星は何を恐れているのでしょうか?
Just go to the next planet after this
この惑星の次の惑星に行くだけです
Does anyone know
誰か知っていますか
where is he going
彼はどこへ行くのですか
Next target
次のターゲット
Does anyone know
誰か知っていますか
Guess
推測
There are so many planets in the universe
宇宙にはたくさんの惑星があります
Now, of course, the light pollution of the special style is relatively tight.
さて、もちろん、特別なスタイルの光害は比較的タイトです。
If you go for diplomacy, take a look
外交に行くならぜひ見てください
Wow, that star is too many to count
うわー、あの星は数え切れないほどたくさんあるよ
I went back to my home in Nantou a while ago
先ほど南投の家に帰ってきました
come with some relatives
親戚何人かと一緒に来る
Wow, they looked at it and said wow, why is this
わあ、彼らはそれを見て、わあ、なぜこれだと言った
There are so many stars in Nantou
南投には星がたくさんあります
and then the terrible
そして恐ろしいこと
have a child like this
こんな子供がいる
She clicked on this phone or that app
彼女はこの電話とそのアプリをクリックしました
She calls out every star
彼女はあらゆる星を呼び出す
OK now just say
OK、今言ってください
Your GPS knows where your location is
GPS はあなたの位置を認識します
The second you know when your date is
デートの日時がわかった瞬間に
Every star on her phone
彼女の携帯電話の中のすべてのスター
Correspond to the stars in your sky one by one
あなたの空の星一つ一つに対応して
We used to get half a day there
以前はそこで半日かかっていました
Oh, which one is the Big Dipper?
ああ、北斗七星はどれですか？
oh which one is the star
ああ、どっちがスターだよ
right now no more
今はもうない
Take it out and pair it up
取り出してペアリングする
Oh this is her this is her
ああ、これは彼女です、これは彼女です
This kid seems to be very happy now
この子は今とても幸せそうです
won't probably lose some of the fun too
おそらく楽しみも失われることはないだろう
what to say
嗯 いう的
This nautical plus to the last star star
この航海プラスを最後のスタースターに
It's actually been, maybe three or four years ago
実は3～4年前くらいかな
He ran from the earth for forty years
彼は40年間地球から逃げました
Then of course you can design him and see how long he goes around
もちろん、彼をデザインして、どれくらい長く回るかを確認することもできます
But it takes years to go between each star
しかし、それぞれの星の間を移動するには何年もかかります
OK, run like this
よし、このまま走れ
ok , to the back
オーケー、後ろへ
Of course he can wait and say, then I'll go out
もちろん、彼は待って、それから出かけますと言うことができます
It may take many years to wait, and it is possible to go to the next planet
何年もかかるかもしれないが、次の惑星に行くことも可能だ
But maybe two or three hundred years later
でも多分200年か300年後
Do you have the impression that we are talking about the distance between the stars
星と星の間の距離について話しているような印象を受けますか?
Of course, there are tens of thousands of light years, or even hundreds of millions of light years.
もちろん、数万光年、あるいは数億光年もあります。
That's just running away, not man would have already run away
それはただ逃げているだけだ もう誰も逃げていないでしょう
Man-made numbers that can run may be 1/1000th of light
人工的に走れる数値は光の1000分の1かもしれない
that means
つまり
There are many galaxies, but space is still very lonely
銀河はたくさんありますが、宇宙はまだとても寂しいです
You're going from one solar system to the next
あなたはある太陽系から次の太陽系へ移動します
And it might be a long, long time
そしてそれは長い長い時間かもしれない
So, here I will make a picture
ということで、ここで写真を撮ります
This is Eston, when he joined NASA very young
こちらはエストン、若くしてNASAに入社した頃
This is him two years ago, our thermoelectric society
これは2年前の彼です、私たちの熱電社会
In Pasadena, at the Celtic
パサデナのケルティックで
Eston came to tell us the story of Voyager
エストンはボイジャーの話をしに来ました
what does that mean? i want to tell him that means
それはどういう意味ですか？彼にそれを伝えたいです
be his baby, his baby
彼の赤ちゃんになってください、彼の赤ちゃんになってください
when done from here
ここから終わったら
He is also in his seventies, seventies or eighties
彼も70代、70代、あるいは80代だ
He's as ready as a spaceship
彼は宇宙船のように準備ができています
retired
退職した
It does sound a bit sentimental.
それは少しセンチメンタルに聞こえます。
But it's also pretty
でもそれもきれいだよ
how to say
どのように言って
A sense of accomplishment
達成感
your mission has been
あなたの使命は
the way to go
該走的路
The planets that should be explored have already been explored
探索すべき惑星はすでに探索されている
from here to here
ここからここまで
so it's an interesting story
それは興味深い話です
Of course what we are going to tell today is not his story.
もちろん、今日私たちが話そうとしているのは彼の話ではありません。
what we're going to talk about is this
私たちが話そうとしているのはこれです
use him to generate electricity
彼を使って発電する
For example, this is another new one
たとえば、これも新しいものです
Mars
火星
You can use solar panels on Mars
火星でもソーラーパネルが使える
no no no
ダメダメダメ
The power of solar panels is still limited
太陽光パネルの発電量にはまだ限界がある
So it's this Mars rover
これが火星探査機です
Now it's about going to explore Mars.
今度は火星を探索することになります。
then you can smooth this
そうすればこれを滑らかにすることができます
after landing
着陸後
your cars
あなたの車
You need pretty high power for this
これにはかなり高い電力が必要です
still want
まだ欲しい
Use this RTG, this radioactive thermoelectric, to generate electricity
このRTG、この放射性熱電を使用して発電します
So everyone can go from here
だからみんなここから行けるよ
You can feel that this thermal power has indeed made a very important contribution
この火力は確かに非常に重要な貢献をしていることが感じられます。
especially in space
特に宇宙では
Then let's look at this thermoelectric conversion and many mathematical things
それでは、この熱電変換と多くの数学的なことを見てみましょう
let's not talk too much
あまり話さないようにしましょう
But this thing has a Figure Marriage
しかし、これには結婚の姿があります
What do we call optimization factor
最適化係数とは何ですか
Basically it has an upstairs and a downstairs
基本的には上階と下階があります
good
良い
It has an upstairs and a downstairs and multiplied by the temperature
上階と下階があり、温度を掛け合わせます。
The bigger you go upstairs, the better
上の階に行けば行くほど良い
The lower the downstairs, the better
階下が低ければ低いほど良い
Upstairs is the thermoelectric coefficient we just talked about
上の階は先ほど話した熱電係数です
C-back coefficient
Cバック係数
Then there's an electrical conductivity here
ここには導電性があります
You said that the higher the conductivity, the greater the C-back coefficient
導電率が高いほどC-back係数が大きくなると言いましたね
that's better
その方が良いです
Downstairs is the heat transfer coefficient
階下は熱伝達率です
That leads to the smaller the better
つまり小さいほど良いということになります
then if you can put this to play with it
これを使って遊べるなら
You can get better with this thermoelectric material
この熱電材料を使用すると改善できます
but it's interesting
でも面白いです
In the past if you came to see
昔、見に来てくれたら
This past human development
過去の人類の発展
Seven years from the 1940s to 1960
1940年代から1960年までの7年間
Wow this is a little bit of progress
おお、これはちょっとした進歩だ
In fact
実際には
From 670 to 2000
670年から2000年まで
this
これ
This optimization factor is always below 1
この最適化係数は常に 1 未満です
what's even
何が平らか
some people doubt that
それを疑う人もいる
ah this
ああ、これ
Is this optimization factor
これは最適化係数ですか
This maximum value
この最大値は
must be small 1
小さいはずです 1
It means there is no hope
希望がないということです
I thought everyone would
みんなそうなると思ってた
if
もしも
I mentioned it here
ここで言及しました
What if you want this optimization factor?
この最適化係数が必要な場合はどうすればよいでしょうか?
If you want a sophomore
２年生が欲しいなら
It has the scrap meat we just talked about
先ほど話したスクラップ肉が入っています
waste meat recycling
廃肉のリサイクル
what else
ほかに何か
our
私たちの
What is the name of this one in Yangmingshan?
陽明山のこれは何という名前ですか？
geothermal
地熱
With this thing, a lot of energy can be recovered
これでエネルギーが大量に回復できる
but you have to be good enough
しかし、十分に良くなければなりません
Or
また
The air conditioner in your home or the one we are using now
あなたのご自宅のエアコン、または現在使用しているエアコン
The most important thing for an air conditioner is a compressor
エアコンにとって最も重要なものはコンプレッサーです
that compressor
そのコンプレッサー
Although the efficiency is very good, it is very efficient
効率は非常に良いですが、非常に効率的です
Then if you want to compete with the compressor
次に、コンプレッサーと競合したい場合は、
Your optimization factor should be greater than 4
最適化係数は 4 より大きくなければなりません
So let's see how much everyone has done so far.
それでは、みんながこれまでどれだけのことをしてきたかを見てみましょう。
As just mentioned, most of them are below 1
先ほど述べたように、それらのほとんどは 1 未満です。
By the year 2000 or so
2000年くらいまでに
got up from the start
最初から起きた
Everyone gave up
みんな諦めた
What is this year 2000?
今年は 2000 年何年ですか?
Clinton announced that
クリントン氏はこう発表した
this
これ
National Science, the nanoscience initiative
ナショナル サイエンス、ナノサイエンス イニシアチブ
It's Congress passing a lot of money for the scientific community to do nanoscience.
科学界がナノサイエンスを行うために多額の資金を議会が通過させているのだ。
After the nano science is down, the part of the material, the nano material
ナノサイエンスが崩壊した後、材料の一部、ナノ材料
There are many, many improvements that make this a considerable improvement
非常に多くの改善点があり、これは大幅な改善となっています
However, although there has been an improvement, it is probably still below two
ただし、改善はされていますが、おそらくまだ 2 を下回っています。
Especially, the real industrial application is only in this generation
特に本格的な産業応用はこの世代になってから
If you want to exceed two, now at most you will occasionally report in the laboratory
2を超えたい場合は、今はせいぜい研究室で時々報告するだけです
So, there is still a long way to go for this development
したがって、この開発にはまだ長い道のりがあります
Let’s look at it again, that is to say, most of this was done in the past, because
もう一度見てみましょう。つまり、これのほとんどは過去に行われたものです。
So this heat conduction is getting lower and lower
この熱伝導はどんどん低くなっていきます
Instead, the part of the above molecule that needs to be elevated
代わりに、上記の分子のうち上昇させる必要がある部分が
not much improvement
あまり改善されない
That light reduces the heat conduction
その光は熱伝導を減らします
it's not enough
足りません
how do you get in
どうやって入るの？
can change the material
素材を変えることができる
its electronic structure
その電子構造
Etc., etc
などなど
there's a lot to do
やるべきことがたくさんある
let's not talk too much today
今日はあまり話さないようにしましょう
went deep
深くなった
but let everyone feel
でもみんなに感じてもらいましょう
For example, we just talked about your house
たとえば、先ほどあなたの家の話をしました。
Is this complex
これはコンプレックスですか
Still a regular house
まだ普通の家
then it has different materials
それからそれは異なる材料を持っています
Here is 1.0
ここは1.0です
1.0 is here
1.0はこちら
most of the material
材料のほとんどが
In fact, it is all lower than 1
実際にはすべて 1 より小さいです
there are a few
いくつかあります
can be higher than 1
1より大きくてもよい
then here
それからここで
At the same time, I want to tell everyone
同時に皆さんにもお伝えしたいのですが、
these materials
これらの材料
You said the Bismuth Terrarium we just talked about is good
さっき話したビスマステラリウムが良いって言ってたね
It can have a good oil coefficient at very low temperature
非常に低い温度でも優れたオイル係数を得ることができます
But it's only good at certain temperatures
ただし、それは特定の温度でのみ有効です
The Silicon Jomainium that was just mentioned is going to space.
先ほどのシリコン・ジョマイニウムは宇宙に行く予定です。
it's not very high
あまり高くありません
But it can go to very high temperature
しかし、非常に高温になる可能性があります
and then all behaved well
それからみんな行儀よく行動した
Then your radioactive element can provide very high temperature
そうすれば、放射性元素は非常に高い温度を提供する可能性があります
so just right for it
ちょうどいいです
Every material it is not omnipotent
すべての物質は万能ではありません
It is only in a certain temperature range
ある温度範囲内でのみ発生します
is the temperature at which it behaves well
正常に動作する温度です
So it depends on what you want to use
したがって、何を使いたいかによって異なります
if you want to cool down
クールダウンしたい場合は
then climb down
それから降ります
come down
降りてくる
If you want to generate electricity, go up
発電したいなら上へ上がれ
If you want to use the waste heat of the car
車の廃熱を利用したい場合
your exhaust pipe comes out
排気管が出てきます
about 800
約800
400 to 800 degrees, this one, this one
400度から800度、これ、これ。
Therefore, there may be a lot of research and development needed
したがって、多くの研究開発が必要になる可能性があります
we'll see this later
これは後で見てみましょう
This thing, these parameters
これ、このパラメータ
it is, it's not that simple, it's interactive
それはそれほど単純ではありません、それはインタラクティブです
For example, this is α, this is the thermoelectric parameter, and this is
たとえば、これは α、これは熱電パラメータ、これは
When you change something, it comes down
何かを変えると、それは下がる
But, among them, the conductivity number, the heavier it goes up
ただし、その中でも導電率の数値は大きくなるほど重くなります
Then you are like a see-saw, this side is higher and this side is lower
そうすると君はシーソーみたいになって、こっちが高くてこっちが低い
Come down and go, or there is a saying in Minnan dialect
閩南地方の方言で「降りて来い」という諺があります。
It's better to describe it as Yagu Zhaobi
形容得比較好叫,雅姑昭比
You, when you came to this side, this side ran away again
あなたはこちら側に来たのに、またこちら側に逃げてしまった
So, we are playing with this material, thermoelectric material
それで、私たちはこの材料、熱電材料で遊んでいます
The factory manager doesn't make materials as usual
工場長はいつものように材料を作らない
i want to see models, i don't just
モデルを見たいだけじゃない
Just make it bigger
ただ大きくしてください
No, your side is big
いいえ、あなたの側面は大きいです
Here is a small set
ちょっとしたセットはこちら
so it's not easy
だからそれは簡単ではない
OK
OK
that now there are many
今はたくさんあるということ
various materials
さまざまな素材
I think I'm not going into details
詳細には触れないと思います
It has a resistant rice structure
耐性のある米の構造を持っています
some put some material
いくつかの材料を置く人もいます
will keep it in
それを保管します
This we call Rethylene
これをレチレンと呼びます
let it over there
そこに任せてください
this student
この学生
when it's hot
暑いとき
it will be over there
そこにあるでしょう
vibrating inside
内部で振動している
Then let the heat go down easily
その後、熱を簡単に下げてください
There are even some materials that say
と言う資料もあります。
it looks solid though
見た目はしっかりしてるけど
But in fact it's like a liquid inside
でも実際は中身は液体のようなもの
The heat will be more difficult to pass
熱が伝わりにくくなる
blah blah blah
何とか何とか何とか
That is the same as, for example, Nami structural materials
それは例えばナミ構造材と同じです
how are you like this
調子はどうですか
Different we call Grain
異なるものをグレインと呼びます
big or small
大なり小なり
or there is this
またはこれがあります
with raisins, or with this sandwich biscuit in it
レーズン入り、またはこのサンドイッチビスケット入り
Various materials now
今では様々な素材が
it's all there now
それはもうそこにあります
lots to do
やるべきことがたくさんある
Just now this was a trial intention
ただ今、これはお試しのつもりです
this is
これは
What can be seen in the experimental materials
実験材料から何がわかるのか
good
良い
What about us
私たちについてはどうでしょうか
what about the laboratory
研究室はどうですか
just mentioned
先ほど述べた
This Silicon Jominium
このシリコンジョミニウム
It has been proven, put it in the tire cavity and use it again
実証済み、タイヤ空洞に入れて再度使用
Eh
えー
We say carbon finer
カーボンファインターと言います
right
右
carbon fine
碳細者
wash
洗う
ah
ああ
then pull
それから引っ張ります
that row
その列
But Silicon Jominium can
しかし、シリコン・ジョミニウムは可能です。
Then Silicon Tin can do it
それならシリコンスズでもできる
wash
洗う
wash heel
かかとを洗う
wash and wash
洗って洗って
These two are in the same row
この二つは同じ列にあります
The electronic structure is almost
電子構造はほぼ
only
それだけ
this ratio
この比率
This washing is heavier than folding
この洗濯物はたたむより重いです
The heavier the thermoelectric material, the better.
熱電材料は重いほど優れています。
the heavier the words
言葉が重ければ重いほど
Its heat transfer will be slower
熱伝達が遅くなります
so what
だから何
we just wanna say wow
私たちはただすごいと言いたいだけです
then this will be better than this
そうすれば、これはこれよりも良くなるでしょう
let's try
やってみよう
Those who work on materials will know
素材を扱っている人ならわかると思いますが、
These two things never mix
この 2 つは決して混ざることはありません
you put them in one by one
あなたはそれらを一つずつ入れます
as soon as the temperature drops
気温が下がるとすぐに
separate soon
すぐに別れる
impossible to be an alloy
合金になるのは不可能
Then we said
それから私たちは言いました
Impossible to alloy it doesn't matter
合金化は不可能ですが関係ありません
then i'll let you make this
じゃあこれ作らせてあげるよ
We are called non-golden statues
私たちは黄金ではない彫像と呼ばれています
Amorphous
まとまりのない
what about Amorphous
アモルファスはどうですか
then we start researching
それから調査を始めます
Recently there seems to be a sign
最近その兆しが見えてきた
I can't explain it to you here.
ここでは説明できません。
one direction like this
このように一方向
we are actually doing now
私たちは今実際にやっています
even say
さえ言う
if these two
この二人なら
won't mix
混ざりません
This prisoner, I'll leave as soon as I see you
この囚人よ、あなたに会ったらすぐに出発します
Then can I use three, a love triangle
じゃあ、三角関係の3つを使ってもいいですか？
It's a big deal between two people, let's put the third one in
二人の間では大事なことだ、三人目を入れよう
Magnetium Silicon Tin
マグネチウムシリコンスズ
It is possible, in fact this material has been used a lot in thermoelectric materials
実際、この材料は熱電材料に多く使用されている可能性があります。
studied a lot
たくさん勉強しました
Of course it's very important
もちろんそれは重要です
For example, although the material is very good
たとえば、素材はとても良いのですが、
But you can tell when you see the material
でも資料を見れば分かるよ
If you don't touch this Germanium, you better not touch it
このゲルマニウムに触れないなら触らないほうがいいです
because it's expensive
高価なので
It is probably more than a hundred times that of Silicon
おそらくシリコンの100倍以上
So you have a lot of money just to buy materials
材料を買うだけでもかなりのお金がかかります
But you said Silicon and Tin, laundry and drama
でも君はシリコンとブリキ、洗濯物とドラマって言ったね
Both of these are many on the surface
どちらも表面上はたくさんあります
So it's cheap in comparison
比較すると安いので
But the two don't touch together
しかし二人は触れ合わない
what to do
何をすべきか
Magnetism Silicon Tin
磁性シリコン錫
This is also cheap
これも安いです
The second and third are cheaper
2番目と3番目は安いです
then this looks good
それならこれは良さそうです
So Japan in this regard
したがって、この点において日本は
great effort
大変な努力
so let everyone
だからみんなもそうしましょう
Feel it, so what materials can you play with
触ってみて、どんな素材で遊べるの
for example
例えば
Germanium Terulium
ゲルマニウム テルリウム
this is also a
これもまた
our normal one
私たちの普通のもの
Used in your home
あなたの家で使われている
DVDs, CDs
ＤＶＤ、ＣＤ
Once the laser is fired, it will
レーザーが発射されると、
in disguise
変装した
So use this to remember
だからこれを使って覚えてください
memory for CD
CD用メモリ
already used a lot
すでにたくさん使用されています
We found that it
私たちはそれを発見しました
Mainly like this battery
このバッテリーとほとんど同じです
We also recently got some
私たちも最近いくつか入手しました
effect, looks
効果、見た目
It's really good, although it's inside
中なのにすごくいいです
This Germanium is quite expensive
このゲルマニウムはかなり高価です
Terulium is not cheap either
テルリウムも安くない
but
しかし
from research
研究から
OK
OK
ok good
いいよ
this is a
これは
uh just arrived
ああ、ちょうど到着したところです
Professor Zhiwei Zhang from Ningtai Center
寧台センターのZhiwei Zhang教授
he brought it up
彼はそれを持ち出した
He said you just put two, two episodes
彼は、2、2 つのエピソードを入れただけだと言いました
one can one hot one cold
1 つはホット、もう 1 つは冷たい
It's over
終わりました
uh this is not enough
ああ、これでは十分ではありません
He uses three-stage
彼は3段階を使用します
Thermoelectric materials are
熱電材料は、
uh sorry
ああ、ごめんなさい
I
私
good
良い
again
また
So what about Professor Zhang Zhiwei?
では、張志偉教授はどうでしょうか？
he just
ちょうど彼
does not pose a method
不pose一個方法
Say you have three temperatures
3 つの温度があるとします。
one
一
two, three
二、三
Then this material is very special
それから、この素材は非常に特別です
He thinks that if this material is a material called
この物質が と呼ばれる物質であれば、と彼は考えます。
When electricity or heat is transmitted, it is called
電気や熱が伝わることをこう呼びます。
is one is one
一つです 一つです
Belistic
ベリスティック
that is
あれは
Not the usual diffuser
普通のディフューザーではなく、
but a bullet-like transmission
しかし弾丸のような伝達
In this way you can get
このようにして、あなたは得ることができます
higher efficiency
より高い効率
Then it is still working hard
それならまだ頑張ってるよ
In addition
加えて
The laboratory of Academician Wu Maokun
呉茂坤院士の研究室
It uses one called Aerogel
エアロゲルというものを使用しています
Aerogel is a
エアロゲルは、
Oxide-based materials
酸化物系材料
But it is a very
しかし、それは非常に
Sponge-like oxidation system
スポンジ状の酸化システム
Oxidizing system because it can withstand very high heat
非常に高い熱に耐えることができるため、酸化系
so what
だから何
it won't dissolve
溶けないよ
For example, this is a torch and a flame
たとえば、これはトーチと炎です
It burns in this Aerogel
このエアロゲルの中で燃えます
The L of the crab is on the bottom, and a flower is placed on it, it will not be affected
カニのLが下にあり、その上に花が置かれていますが、影響を受けません
So it conducts heat very, very low
したがって、熱伝導率は非常に低いです
So Academician Wu combined this material with existing thermoelectric materials
そこでウー学者は、この材料を既存の熱電材料と組み合わせました。
Then it was found that the parameters of thermoelectricity can be effectively improved
その後、熱電パラメータを効果的に改善できることが判明しました。
Wait, I can't introduce everything
ちょっと待って、すべてを紹介することはできません
This is Professor Chen Lidong in Shanghai
こちらは上海の陳立東教授です
One of the things he did was to say that it develops thermoelectricity. If you were a freshman in thermoelectricity before
彼がやったことの 1 つは、熱電を開発するということです。
At the beginning you can only use it in space, with a very special
最初は宇宙でのみ使用でき、非常に特別な機能が付いています。
Slowly heat and electricity, if it reaches about 2000
ゆっくりと熱と電気を加え、2000くらいになったら
It has a few more, including this familiar refrigerator and more
このおなじみの冷蔵庫など、他にもいくつかあります
energy available
利用可能なエネルギー
that's it
それでおしまい
What about after 2020?
2020年以降はどうなるでしょうか？
this
これ
its this gt
それはこれです
freshman
新入生
even up to 1.5
1.5まででも
Slowly it can be used in the car
徐々に車内でも使えるようになります
etc.
等
It is more and more widely used
ますます便利です
that's like i said
それは私が言ったようなものです
if you really want to be useful
本当に役に立ちたいなら
Still have to go to 2.0
まだ2.0に行かなければなりません
or 4.0
または4.0
is it possible to get there
そこに行くことは可能ですか
Now everyone is still working hard
今もみんな頑張ってるよ
I'll make one with him
彼と一緒に一つ作りましょう
current difficulties
現在の困難
What about the difficulty?
難易度はどうですか？
The first is that it is not efficient enough
1つ目は、効率が十分ではないということです
usually
いつもの
about 10%
約10％
10% is
10%は
already very high
すでに非常に高い
but
しかし
if you come to tell
伝えに来たら
If you want to generate electricity
発電したいなら
e.g. solar
例: 太陽光発電
or wind energy
または風力エネルギー
What about solar energy?
太陽エネルギーについてはどうですか？
has long been proven
長い間証明されてきた
He said he is now the cheapest of all energy sources
現在、すべてのエネルギー源の中で最も安価であると彼は言いました
That
それか
We are all looking for alternative energy now
私たちは今、代替エネルギーを探しています
I can cut it right here
ここで切れますよ
that is
あれは
Alternative Energy of the Future
将来の代替エネルギー
This solar is mainstream
この太陽光発電が主流です
The second is wind power
2つ目は風力発電です
What about wind power?
風力発電はどうですか？
recently
最近
Well
良い
also from
からも
The original price has been reduced to
元の価格は以下に値下げされました
ha
はぁ
and
と
This thermal power generation
この火力発電は
Similar to traditional thermal power generation
従来の火力発電と同様
That
それか
This thing is of course similar to the energy transformation we are doing in Taiwan.
これはもちろん、私たちが台湾で行っているエネルギー変革と似ています。
Then our government is also developing these two areas
そして、私たちの政府もこれら 2 つの分野を開発しています
ha
はぁ
Although that said
そうは言っても
They are all
それらはすべて
Very Potential Very Cheap
非常に潜在的 非常に安価
ha
はぁ
but
しかし
The first one you have to invest in earlier
早めに投資しなければならないもの
the second
二番目
they don't exist forever
彼らは永遠に存在するわけではない
And what if there is no sun in this cover transit today?
そして、今日このカバートランジットに太陽がなかったらどうなるでしょうか？
you will be gone
あなたはいなくなるでしょう
Or there is no wind today
それとも今日は風が無いのかな
your wind stops
あなたの風が止まる
Then you sometimes do and sometimes don't
それから、時々そうすることもあれば、しないこともあります
It involves the storage of electricity as an energy source
エネルギー源としての電気の貯蔵が含まれます
that is becoming very very important
それはとてもとても重要になってきています
There may be many colleagues here
ここには同僚がたくさんいるかもしれない
all in
全部入り
related to this research
この研究に関連する
That
それか
but anyway
とにかく
anyway
ともかく
if this
これなら
like germany
ドイツのように
they from that
彼らはそこから
Japanese style
日本的
that tsunami
あの津波
three one
三一
after
後
they suddenly
彼らは突然
awakened over night said
一晩中目が覚めて言った
Let's not go nuclear in the future
将来的には原発はやめましょう
Nuclear power will be abolished in a few years
原発は数年以内に廃止される
they actively go
彼らは積極的に行きます
That one is these two, wind energy and solar energy
それはこの2つ、風力エネルギーと太陽エネルギーです。
Well they confirmed today
さて、彼らは今日確認しました
Prove that this is a feasible solution
これが実現可能な解決策であることを証明する
He has confirmed that step by step
彼はそれを段階的に確認した
Of course it is impossible to say within a year or two
もちろん1年や2年以内とは言えませんが、
He can phase out this future nuclear power step by step
彼は将来の原子力発電を段階的に廃止できるだろう
Even this petrochemical raw material in the future
この石油化学原料も将来的には
Coal or oil or natural gas
石炭とか石油とか天然ガスとか
The whole step by step use this
全体のステップごとにこれを使用します
We call sustainable green energy
私たちは持続可能なグリーンエネルギーと呼んでいます
can be used in the future
将来的に使用できる
green energy to replace
代替となるグリーンエネルギー
That
それか
but
しかし
he needs a while
彼には少し時間が必要だ
What is your government's plan?
政府の計画は何ですか?
how determined are you
あなたはどのくらい決意していますか
but
しかし
Such alternative energy
このような代替エネルギー
Is it possible to use thermoelectricity?
熱電を利用することは可能ですか？
Thermoelectricity is far worse than it
熱電はそれよりはるかに悪い
General Solar
一般的な太陽光発電
you are in the lab now
あなたは今研究室にいます
Simply more than 20%
単純に20％以上
In the market you can buy 15%
市場では15%で買える
15% complete
完了15%
Then you have to say 5% of our thermal power
そうすると、火力発電の 5% と言わざるを得ません。
right it's hard how you compete
そう、どうやって競争するかは難しい
so i'm going to talk to him later
だから後で彼と話すつもりだ
If you want to develop thermoelectricity
熱電を開発したいなら
you want to use it for a very special purpose
非常に特別な目的に使用したい
Our name is Niche Application
私たちの名前はニッチアプリケーションです
What about this special purpose?
この特別な目的についてはどうですか？
The most special thing is the spaceship
最も特別なものは宇宙船です
then it really needs it
それなら本当に必要だ
Only it can take on this responsibility
この責任を負えるのはそれだけです
Are there any others?
他にもありますか？
is there any other
他にありますか
Our name is Niche Application
私たちの名前はニッチアプリケーションです
talk later
等一下再談
In addition
加えて
One is its high material cost
一つは材料費が高いこと
you say i put it...
私が置いたって言ってるよ…
it mounts on the car
車に取り付けます
Then I can increase the mileage by 10%
そうすれば走行距離を10％増やすことができます
Very good, 10% is also 10%
とても良いです、10％も10％です
if i had this when i bought it
買ったときにこれがあれば
Then I save 10%
そうすれば10％節約できます
but
しかし
Current thermoelectric materials are too expensive
現在の熱電材料は高価すぎる
so what
だから何
Your previous investment was too high
前回の投資が高すぎました
that can only be tested again
それはもう一度テストすることしかできない
You can't really use this for people's livelihood
これは本当に人の暮らしのために使えない
So how to develop this material
では、この素材をどのように開発するかというと、
Don't use that expensive material
そんな高価な素材は使わないでください
use cheap materials
用便宜的材料
is also an important point
も重要なポイントです
good
良い
but
しかし
when we talk about energy
エネルギーについて話すとき
especially when it comes to alternative energy
特に代替エネルギーに関しては
many people will make some mistakes
多くの人は間違いを犯すでしょう
idea or imagination
アイデアや想像力
for example
例えば
Use water as energy
水をエネルギーとして利用する
what day is it
今日は何日ですか
That day the dean
その日、学部長は
When the dean of the tune gave a speech, there was a speech that said
曲の部長がスピーチをしたとき、次のようなスピーチがありました。
Why
なぜ
Direct water can be used as energy
直接水をエネルギーとして利用できる
why do we still have to buy gasoline
なぜまだガソリンを買わなければならないのですか
Why do we still want to develop nuclear energy
なぜ私たちは原子力エネルギーを開発したいのか
Why develop thermal power
なぜ火力発電を開発するのか
right
右
Can water be used as energy?
水はエネルギーとして利用できるのでしょうか？
can anyone answer
誰か答えられますか
water as energy
エネルギーとしての水
Then we can use carbon dioxide as energy
そうすれば二酸化炭素をエネルギーとして利用できる
carbon dioxide more
二酸化炭素が増える
our this
私たちのこれ
it will produce this global warming
それはこの地球温暖化を引き起こすでしょう
We use it as energy
私たちはそれをエネルギーとして利用します
water as energy
エネルギーとしての水
Water can be used as energy
水はエネルギーとして利用できる
you put this water
あなたはこの水を入れます
break it down into
に分解する
hydrogen and oxygen
水素と酸素
What about the hydrogen?
水素はどうでしょうか？
You can use fuel cells and so on
燃料電池なども使えます
use it
これを使って
That
それか
People say it is the cleanest energy
人々はそれが最もクリーンなエネルギーだと言います
because when you use
なぜなら、使用するときは
Hydrogen turns into water again
水素は再び水に戻ります
So no pollution at all
だから汚染はまったくない
correct
正しい
but
しかし
you have to turn water into
水を次のように変えなければなりません
Cyan and oxygen
シアンと酸素
then you have many ways
それならいろいろな方法があります
The most common method is to use electrolysis
最も一般的な方法は電気分解を使用することです
our middle school
私たちの中学校
Even elementary school nature lessons
小学校の自然教室でも
I've done it for everyone to see
みんなに見てもらえるようにやりました
How did that call come from?
その電話はどのようにして来たのですか？
Most of the electricity still comes from
電力のほとんどは今でも
power plant out
発電所がなくなった
so
それで
not impossible
不可能ではない
we say
私達は言う
I said before that you are generating electricity
前にも言いましたが、発電しているんですね
What do you use electricity to electrolyze water for?
電気を使って水を電気分解するのは何ですか?
cleanest and best
最もクリーンで最高の
Why are you going to electrolyze water?
なぜ水を電気分解するのですか？
Does anyone know
誰か知っていますか
disable
無効にする
that is
あれは
your nuclear power plant
あなたの原子力発電所
or your many power plants
またはあなたの多くの発電所
you can't switch
切り替えることはできません
then you when you
それからあなたは
At night you still have power left
夜になってもまだ電力は残っている
what to do
何をすべきか
deplete its electrolyzed water
電解水を使い果たす
when you run out of power
電力がなくなったとき
when the sun doesn't have the sun
太陽がないとき
You generate electricity like this
こうやって発電するんですね
that so
まあまあ
It is said that water can be used as energy
水はエネルギーとして利用できると言われています
This is only one tenth right
これはわずか 10 分の 1 です
It didn't talk about how the water turns into hydrogen, right?
水がどのようにして水素に変わるのかは説明されていませんでしたね。
that's the real difficulty
それが本当の難しさだ
like many labs including mine
私を含む多くの研究室と同様に
Still researching how to electrolyze water
水を電気分解する方法を研究中
It is to make the efficiency of electrolysis of water higher
水の電気分解効率を高めるためです
take its material
その材料を取る
Because it used to be made of platinum or something.
昔はプラチナか何かでできていたからです。
reduce it
それを減らす
how much time do we have
時間はどれくらいありますか
We were just 8.5
私たちはちょうど8.5歳でした
8.5
８。５
that other thing
他のこと
It would be good to say that air is the motive force of the car.
車の原動力は空気と言ってもいいでしょう。
Why do you have this air everywhere
なぜどこにでもこの空気があるのですか
You see people have taken some countries
人々がいくつかの国を占領したのがわかります
has proven it this bus
このバスがそれを証明しました
run on air
空気で走る
And it sounds a lot like the real thing
そしてそれは本物のように聞こえます
it also proves to you
それはあなたにも証明されます
This blows air in
これで空気が入ります
It can run dozens of kilometers in one run
一度の走行で数十キロも走れる
what it didn't say
言われなかったこと
You compress this air into
この空気を圧縮すると、
Look at the top ten atmospheric pressure
10 番目の気圧を確認してください
then use that to run
それを使用して実行します
compression process
圧縮プロセス
it just needs electricity
電気が必要なだけです
use motor or oil
モーターやオイルを使う
so what
だから何
not so easy
そう簡単ではない
Are electric cars the cleanest form of energy?
電気自動車は最もクリーンなエネルギー形態ですか?
Methods
メソッド
electric cars of course
もちろん電気自動車
You didn't emit any smoke when you went out
外出するときも煙は出ませんでした
no other waste
他に無駄はありません
right
右
But how does it get electricity
しかしどうやって電気を得るのか
electricity you if not from solar
太陽光発電でない場合でも電気を供給します
you still have to get from the power plant
まだ発電所から行かなければなりません
that power plant has its benefits
あの発電所には利点がある
Its power plant is that it is focused on you
その発電所はあなたに焦点を合わせていることです
If you discharge these
これらを排出すれば、
Carbon dioxide and these waste
二酸化炭素とこれらの廃棄物
you can immediately
すぐにできます
If you filter it before discharging it
排出する前にろ過すれば
then you can reduce the level of air pollution
そうすれば大気汚染のレベルを下げることができます
than say
言うよりも
normal car
普通車
That day the Sixth Dean spoke
その日、第6代学部長はこう話しました。
cars run around
車が走り回る
Once it's out, you can't get it back.
一度出てしまうと元に戻すことはできません。
this has it
これにはそれがある
But it's not an absolute solution
しかし、それは絶対的な解決策ではありません
Well, another one I want to give an example to tell you
さて、もう一つ例を挙げてお話したいと思います
Not all energy sources are equally efficient
すべてのエネルギー源が同じように効率的であるわけではありません
For example, Hawaii, raise your hand if you haven't been to Hawaii
たとえば、ハワイ、ハワイに行ったことがない人は手を挙げてください。
There are many parties in Hawaii
ハワイではパーティーがたくさんあります
There is a party in Hawaii called Big Island
ハワイにはビッグアイランドというパーティーがあります
The biggest Big Island is Hawaiian coffee
最大のビッグアイランドはハワイアンコーヒーです
It is produced in a place called Kona
コナという場所で生産されています。
Hawaii has many volcanoes
ハワイには火山がたくさんあります
Monglowa is a
モングロワは、
Then Killer Whale next to it is still spraying every day
そしてその隣のシャチは今でも毎日スプレーをし続けています
there are so many
とてもたくさんあります
Natural resources, and one of the more interesting natural resources among them
天然資源、そしてその中でも特に興味深い天然資源の 1 つ
He is naturally the same as our Huadong and Rift Valley.
彼は当然、私たちの華東と地溝帯と同じです。
That is, the seaside drop is very, very large
つまり、海辺の落差は非常に大きいです
You may have descended to a depth of hundreds of meters after going out for tens of meters
数十メートル外に出たら数百メートルの深さまで潜ったかもしれない
What's so good about this?
これの何がそんなに良いのでしょうか？
This genius scientist came up with the idea of ​​saying
この天才科学者はこう言うことを思いついた
He went for a measurement and found that
彼は測定に行ったところ、次のことが分かりました
This one drops 1,000 feet, about 300 meters
これは高さ 1,000 フィート、約 300 メートルです
The water temperature is more than 20 degrees different from the water at sea level
水温は海面水と20度以上違う
You have a temperature difference from the mechanics above
上のメカニックとは温度差があります
You can generate power with just a temperature difference
温度差だけで発電できる
Okay, then he's coming, and he's trying to get that one thousand feet
オーケー、それでは彼が来る、そして彼はその1,000フィートに到達する方法を見つけるつもりだ
The water temperature at a depth of 300 meters
水深300メートルの水温
pump up the water
水を汲み上げる
like here
ここのような
wet liquid soil
湿った液体土壌
pump up deep water
深層水を汲み上げる
Then the water temperature difference from sea level is 20 degrees
すると海面との水温の差は20度になります。
Then it needs this temperature difference to drive a Turban generator
ターバン発電機を駆動するにはこの温度差が必要です
It's like 20 degrees water without boiling
沸騰させずに20度の水のようなものです
how enough
どのくらい十分ですか
it doesn't matter
それは問題ではありません
General power plants boil water
一般的な発電所では水を沸騰させます
then go push that warrant
それからその令状を押しに行ってください
it if use an alcohol
アルコールを使用した場合
or use something
もしくは何かを使うか
It has a lower boiling point
沸点が低いのです
it can do the same thing
それは同じことができます
20 degrees temperature difference can be done
20度の温度差でも大丈夫
that's the problem
それが問題です
you pump up the water
あなたは水を汲み上げます
you need electricity
電気が必要です
you need energy
エネルギーが必要です
Then you have to generate electricity
だったら発電すればいいのに
After all, you generate more electricity
結局のところ、より多くの電力を生成します
Or do you use more electricity to pump water?
それとも水を汲み上げるためにより多くの電力を使用しますか?
right
右
good
良い
good question
良い質問
Congress of the United States
米国議会
divided into two
二つに分かれる
Allocated dozens of million
数千万を割り当てた
Then what
じゃあ何
do research for them
彼らのために研究をする
prove
証明
he can generate electricity
彼は発電できる
is the electricity ratio
は電力比率です
use more electricity
もっと電気を使う
wow this
うわーこれ
scientifically
科学的に
big success
大成功
success
成功
OK
OK
but i want to ask
でも聞きたいです
How much do you charge once
1回いくらかかりますか
Probably
おそらく
10 times more than ours
当社の10倍以上
wow that
すごいね
high cost
高価な
what to do
何をすべきか
so
それで
when we talk
私たちが話すとき
wow what energy what energy
うわー、何のエネルギー、何のエネルギー
ah this
ああ、これ
Where is the geothermal heat?
地熱はどこにあるの？
where is the hot spring
温泉はどこですか
first we have to ask
まず最初に尋ねなければなりません
your
あなたの
How much is the electricity you send
送った電気はいくらですか
OK
OK
The second one, for example, when we talk about biomass energy
2つ目は、例えばバイオマスエネルギーについて話すときです。
That sounds good
いいですね
right
右
Biomass is very good in the US and in Canada
米国とカナダではバイオマスが非常に優れています
it has so many forests
とてもたくさんの森がある
It has some long
多少長いものがあります
But there are not many forests in Taiwan
でも台湾には森林が少ない
You get all those digital pages of Taiwan's forest
台湾の森のデジタルページをすべて入手できます
Not enough for Taiwan's current needs
台湾の現在のニーズには不十分
then this is an example
それならこれは一例です
scientifically successful
科学的に成功した
but
しかし
economically worthless
経済的に無価値
then i used to
それから私はかつて
At that time with Professor Chen Jiajun
その時は陳佳軍先生と
There was a meeting at Air Force in the United States
アメリカ空軍で会議がありました
just flow over to see
ただ流れて見るだけ
Just go and see for yourself
行って自分の目で見てください
It's called OTEC
オーテックといいます
Ocean Thermoelectric Conversion
海洋熱電変換
After the result, it was a very surprise
結果が出てからはとても驚きました
First
初め
Of course they do.
もちろんそうです。
power generation
発電
Electricity is expensive
電気代が高い
What to do then he just needs to find
じゃあどうするか、彼はただ見つければいいだけだ
Find a way to subsidize it, right?
それを補助する方法を見つけてくださいね？
how to subsidize
補助金をどうやって出すか
very funny
非常に面白い
After the electricity is generated, the water, yes
電気が発生したら、水が、はい。
deep water called
と呼ばれる深層水
hawaii sound
ハワイサウンド
ocean water
海洋水
ok
Ok
Then he battled
それから彼と戦う
Then fly to Tokyo
それから東京へ飛びます
Ah, it's so scary
ああ、とても怖いです
made a lot of money
大金を儲けた
alright
大丈夫
It's been a few years
数年経ちました
because of that water
あの水のせいで
salty water man
塩辛い水の男
People can't drink
人はお酒が飲めない
So he's going to downplay him, right?
それで彼は彼を軽視するつもりですよね？
Dilution is our general RO
希釈は当社の一般的なROです
reverse osmosis
逆浸透
good
良い
Sell ​​after reverse osmosis
逆浸透後に販売
after a few years
数年後
next to it
その次
that pile of salt
あの塩の山
a bunch of mountains
たくさんの山
Headache?
頭痛嘛
right? what should he do?
そうでしょう？彼は何をすべきですか？
then he said
それから彼は言いました
then thought of saying
それからこう言うことを考えた
pack the salt
塩を詰める
Air freight to Japan for sale
日本への航空貨物販売
Raw water
原水
raw sea
生の海
what kind of salt is this
これは何の塩ですか
sold out
完売
that's not all
それがすべてではありません
when we went to see
私たちが見に行ったとき
They also did an experiment
彼らは実験も行いました
Said the water pumped from here
ここから水が汲み上げられているとのこと
to raise those seafood
その魚介類を育てるために
than this
これより
Seafood grown from water on the sea
海の水から育った魚介類
Raised too much
上げすぎた
good
良い
In the end it doesn't matter at all
結局全然関係ないよ
really earning extra money
本当に余分なお金を稼ぐ
That
それか
You say it's a bit sarcastic
あなたはそれが少し皮肉だと言います
but also
だけでなく、
And at least he proved a lot of things, okay?
そして少なくとも彼は多くのことを証明しましたね？
good
良い
we have a chance
私たちにはチャンスがある
For example, this car
たとえば、この車
Then you say you come out of the engine
それからあなたはエンジンから出てくると言います
then to this
それからこれに
Exhaust pipe goes to this
エキゾーストパイプはここまで来ます
we need noodle drinkers or something
ヌードルドリンカーか何かが必要だ
The temperature here ranges from 700 to 800 to 600 to 500 to 400
ここの温度は700度から800度、600度、500度、400度の範囲です。
So what you need to say here is that you want to do thermoelectricity
ここで言う必要があるのは、熱電をやりたいということです
The materials you want are different
欲しい素材が違う
mean to say
言う意味
We still have a lot of rice bowls to eat
まだまだ食べたい丼がたくさんあります
can study a lot
たくさん勉強できる
again now there is
また今あります
you can buy it in the market
市場で購入できます
this is
これは
Get $100 off the internet and you can buy a refrigerator
インターネットで 100 ドル割引すれば冷蔵庫が買える
what about this refrigerator
この冷蔵庫はどうですか
15L
15L
is thermoelectric
熱電です
you may not feel
感じないかもしれない
What is thermal power
火力発電とは何ですか
First
初め
If you want to put a small refrigerator in your car
車に小型冷蔵庫を置きたい場合
put in your suitcase too
スーツケースにも入れてね
too big for you
あなたには大きすぎる
Normal compressor refrigerators are pretty big.
通常のコンプレッサー式冷蔵庫はかなり大きいです。
Because the compressor itself is not small
コンプレッサー自体は小さくないので
Then if you use thermoelectric
次に、熱電を使用する場合
that small is good
小さいのが良い
You might just need a few L's for your energy
エネルギーを得るには、ほんの数個の L が必要かもしれません
except this
これを除いて
I don't know if anyone has the same experience as me
私と同じ経験をした人がいるかどうかはわかりませんが、
you go to a meeting like this
あなたはこのような会議に行きます
then came to a place
それからある場所に来ました
time difference
有時差
can't sleep very troublesome
とても迷惑で眠れません
I can finally fall asleep
やっと眠れます
in that room
あの部屋で
Every now hotel has a refrigerator inside
今ではどのホテルでも室内に冷蔵庫が設置されています
that refrigerator is noisy
その冷蔵庫はうるさいです
finally got up
やっと起きた
Can't turn off that refrigerator
その冷蔵庫の電源を切ることができません
Then unplug it long ago
それならずっと前にコンセントを抜いてください
Why is the refrigerator so noisy
冷蔵庫はなぜあんなにうるさいのか
But if you use this today
でも今日これを使うなら
no sound at all
まったく音が出ない
Once we went abroad in
かつて私たちが海外に行ったとき、
somewhere
どこかで
he declared that he was
彼は自分はそうだと宣言した
this thermoelectric refrigerator
この熱電冷蔵庫
really no sound at all
まったく音が出ない
so what
だから何
he has his special purpose
彼には特別な目的がある
or say you make a
または、あなたが作ると言う
local cooling
局所冷却
cooling is effective
冷却は効果的です
For example, you are
たとえば、あなたは
when driving in a seat
座席に座って運転するとき
there are some parts
いくつかの部分があります
cooling is nice
冷却はいいです
A
あ
currently in use
現在使用中
For example, we used to
たとえば、以前は
There are many detectors in the laboratory
研究室にはたくさんの検出器があります
CCD, infrared
CCD、赤外線
detector
検出器
You have to bring the temperature down
温度を下げなければなりません
Your noise will be reduced
騒音が軽減されます
The cooling of this thermoelectric
この熱電素子の冷却
very effective
非常に効果的
because it doesn't vibrate
振動しないから
So it's less noisy
だから騒音も少ないんだよ
In addition
加えて
have many computers
たくさんのコンピュータを持っています
or your CPU
またはCPU
Your mobile phone is getting better and better
携帯電話はますます高性能になっています
powerful is getting denser and denser
パワフルさはますます濃くなっています
That powerful means that it unit time
パワフルということは単位時間です
It does more and more calculations
どんどん計算が増えていきます
Then the density is more crowded
そうすれば密度はもっと密になります
The heat dissipated per unit time
単位時間あたりに放散する熱量
Higher and higher
高く高く
In fact, many CPU applications
実際、多くの CPU アプリケーションは
not limited to itself
それ自体に限定されない
It's limiting its heat and there's no way to get it out
熱が制限されており、それを取り除く方法はありません
Can't get away
逃げられない
Then if you do a local thermoelectric cooling
次に、局所的な熱電冷却を行うと、
absolutely necessary
絶対に必要な
what about this need
このニーズについてはどうですか
We can look at it from another use
別の用途からも見てみましょう
This is what we call a hydrodynamic missile
これは流体力学ミサイルと呼ばれるものです
Tom Hawk
トム・ホーク
That Tom Hawk missile
あのトムホークミサイル
As soon as the missile flies out
ミサイルが飛び出すとすぐに
OK you take the map
OK、地図を持って行きましょう
put it in its head
それを頭に入れてください
when it's flying
飛んでいるとき
it will fly along your map
それはあなたの地図に沿って飛んでいきます
how does it know
それはどうやってわかるのですか
Where is it? It relies on the same GPS that everyone uses in cars.
それはどこですか? それは誰もが車で使用しているのと同じ GPS に依存しています。
It's just that it needs to be very precise. Besides whether the left and right will touch the mountain
ただ、左右が山に接触するかどうかだけではなく、非常に正確である必要があります。
It also needs to know the height. Usually our cars don’t count the height.
通常、私たちの車は高さをカウントしません。
It tells you when to turn right and how to turn left
いつ右折すべきか、どのように左折すべきかを教えてくれる
Then when you use it, you know yourself. If you have a mobile phone, you are using GPS.
携帯電話を持っている場合は、GPS を使用していることになります。
Your battery dies in a very short time unless you're plugged in all the time
常に電源に接続していないと、バッテリーはすぐに切れてしまいます
Why because it's been calculating it's been following the signal received from the satellite
衛星から受信した信号に従って計算しているからです。
Instead it says where is my point now
代わりに、今の私のポイントはどこにあるのかが表示されます
The computing power is very high, so here comes
計算能力は非常に高いので、ここに来ます
If you want to guide a missile today, your power is so high
今日ミサイルを誘導したいなら、あなたのハイパワー
That computer burned up quickly so every computer
そのコンピュータはすぐに燃えてしまったので、すべてのコンピュータが
Just now everyone saw that MARLO is the most profitable, and all the money it makes is this money
たった今、誰もが MARLO が最も収益性が高く、MARLO が稼いだお金はすべてこのお金であることに気づきました。
are used on missiles
ミサイルに使用されている
OK, so you know this we call Niche application
OK、これをニッチ アプリケーションと呼んでいます。
is the special purpose, the localized cooling of the cooling
特殊な目的、冷却の局所冷却です
In addition, I want to tell you about the many thermoelectric devices developed in South Korea called Kawashiro-style flexible
また、韓国で開発された川城式フレキシブル熱電素子の数々についてもお伝えしたいと思います。
Will it work, I don't know
うまくいきますか、わかりません
Then when I read it, I thought I kept
それからそれを読んだとき、私は保存したと思いました
Because you know your body temperature is 36 degrees
自分の体温が36度であることを知っているからです。
Then your outside is 30 degrees or 25 degrees
その場合、外気温は 30 度または 25 度になります。
This delta T is actually very small, even if it is 10 degrees
このデルタ T は、たとえ 10 度であっても、実際には非常に小さいです。
Then you usually make this material
それで、あなたは通常この材料を作ります
From your contact, the contact itself has some temperature loss
接点から、接点自体にいくらかの温度損失があります
Finally, if you come to a delta T temperature difference of 5 degrees
最終的にデルタT温度差5度まで来たら
In fact, the electricity it can generate will generate electricity, but it will generate very little electricity.
実際、発電できる電気は発電しますが、発電できる電気はほんのわずかです。
whether that will work i don't know
それがうまくいくかどうかはわかりません
South Korea is very very positive
韓国はとてもとても前向きです
He said I might make a
彼は私が作るかも知れないと言いました
very small
非常に少ない
Like some Pace Makers or something
ペースメーカーか何かのように
It would be nice to be able to make a small generator
小型の発電機が作れたら良いですね
another one i was thinking
もう一つ私が考えていたのは
this is a dress
これはドレスです
is it possible
出来ますか
if you can make it flexible
柔軟に対応してもらえれば
Is it possible for
可能ですか？
it's cooler inside
中は涼しいです
Then vent the heat out in the outer layer
そして外側の層で熱を逃がします
You don't need to turn on the air conditioner so much
あまりエアコンをつける必要はありません
India often reaches 50 degrees
インドはしばしば50度に達します
but you wear a cool dress
でもあなたはクールなドレスを着ています
It's very comfortable inside
中はとても快適です
You don't have air conditioners everywhere
どこにでもエアコンがあるわけではない
that thing
その事
It's not impossible
不可能ではありません
You have to generate electricity from your body temperature
体温から電気を生成する必要がある
i find it difficult
それは難しいと思います
but like i said
しかし、私が言ったように
You have to use electricity to be smart
賢くなるためには電気を使わなければなりません
Reporter is okay, is doable
記者は大丈夫、できるよ
Come again, I want to talk about this
また来てね、このことについて話したいんだ
Do you know the football game of this world cup
このワールドカップのサッカーの試合を知っていますか
I didn't look at the chief today
今日は部長を見なかった
Everyone is watching, everyone sees that
みんなが見てる、みんながそれを見てる
Take a few countries, and finally this Championship
いくつかの国を制覇して、最後にこのチャンピオンシップ
France's Creecia, against
フランスのクリーシア、対戦
you know the france team
フランスチームを知っていますか
Finally, special thanks to Taiwan
最後に、台湾に特別な感謝を申し上げます
what good things did we do in taiwan
私たちは台湾でどんな良いことをしましたか
Our jersey sweatshirt
私たちのジャージスウェットシャツ
Taiwan made sweatshirts for their players
台湾は選手のためにスウェットシャツを作った
on the pitch than anything else
何よりもピッチ上で
It's easy to sweat
汗をかきやすい
He especially thanked Taiwan
彼は特に台湾に感謝した
then i mean the same
それなら私も同じ意味です
If you take the heat out
熱を取り除けば
isn't that better
そのほうが良くないですか
You can do it anytime, it's stuffy and hot outside
いつでもできる、外は蒸れて暑い
you feel comfortable
あなたは快適です
it is possible
可能です
so finally i say
それで最後に言います
Thermoelectric has made many great contributions in the past
熱電は過去に多くの大きな貢献をしてきました
but
しかし
In all aspects of efficiency, you are in the niche application
効率のあらゆる側面において、ニッチなアプリケーションに属しています
before it can be used
使えるようになる前に
Then it can't compete with solar and wind power
そうなると太陽光発電や風力発電には勝てない
to compete for this generation
この世代を争うために
How to improve the efficiency so that
そうするために効率を向上させる方法
Even Niche application
ニッチなアプリケーションでも
You also want to lower the price
価格も下げたい
but i think that
でも私はそう思う
What about the future?
将来についてはどうですか？
local cooling
局所冷却
will be where the greater opportunity lies
そこに大きなチャンスがあるだろう
good
良い
I'm here to report to you today
今日はご報告に来ました
Thanks
ありがとう
good
良い
i think such a wonderful speech
とても素晴らしいスピーチだと思います
everyone should have
誰もが持っているはずです
quite a few questions
かなりの数の質問
Whether it is scientific application
科学的応用かどうか
or history
または歴史
i want this
これ欲しい
Teacher Chen has many
チェン先生にはたくさんのことがあります
Information to share with you
あなたと共有する情報
So if you have any questions, you can raise your hands
それでは、質問がある場合は手を挙げてください
Please, can you use the front microphone
フロントマイクを使ってもらえますか
I'm sorry I'm a layman but please advise
素人で申し訳ありませんがアドバイスお願いします
Because it's on the market right now, it's about to happen
今市場に出ているから、もうすぐそうなるだろう
Referendum on Nuclear Oxygen Chlorine Thing
核酸素塩素問題に関する国民投票
what is your opinion
あなたの意見は何ですか
Thanks
ありがとう
This question is quite political.
この質問はかなり政治的です。
Let's not talk about politics, okay?
政治の話はやめましょうね？
Let's not talk about politics, okay? Thank you.
政治の話はやめましょうね? ありがとう。
just say he meant to say
彼が言おうとしていたとだけ言ってください
In your green energy, green energy needs to be developed
グリーン エネルギーでは、グリーン エネルギーを開発する必要があります
i don't think anyone will object
誰も反対しないと思う
The problem is green energy, as I said
先ほども言ったように、問題はグリーンエネルギーです
They can't be in a year or two
1年や2年では無理だよ
even within ten years
たとえ10年以内でも
Humans now include Germany
人類にはドイツも含まれるようになった
Including California has spent a lot of effort
カリフォルニアを含めて多大な労力を費やしました
investing in green energy
グリーンエネルギーへの投資
but his your making
でも彼はあなたが作ったものです
It may take ten years for you to grow up
大人になるには10年かかるかもしれない
It was twenty years later that I arrived at a certain place
二十年後、ある場所にたどり着いた
this amount
この金額
that's okay
大丈夫
Then where the green energy is really developed
では、実際にグリーンエネルギーが開発される場所はどこなのか
I use nuclear power to get by
私は原子力を使って暮らしています
Sounds good to pass the time
暇つぶしには良さそうです
Where is the problem?
問題はどこだ？
The director of the tune also mentioned it that day.
その日、この曲のディレクターもそのことについて言及しました。
first nuclear waste
最初の核廃棄物
That nuclear waste is not a problem in many countries
核廃棄物は多くの国で問題になっていない
like india
インドのように
They are also actively developing their nuclear power
原子力開発も積極的に行っている
France they have the technology to put
フランスには導入する技術がある
This nuclear waste is re-enriched
この核廃棄物は再濃縮される
made smaller and easier to store
より小さくて保管しやすくなりました
but sorry
でもごめんなさい
We don't have that technology in Taiwan
台湾にはその技術がない
Is there any place in Taiwan where nuclear waste can be placed?
台湾に核廃棄物を置ける場所はあるのでしょうか？
I believe that I don't need to tell you
あなたに言う必要はないと信じています
Everyone has been arguing for a long time
みんな長い間喧嘩してる
So if the nuclear waste has nowhere to go
もし核廃棄物が行き場を失ったら
what to do then
それでどうするか
Everyone wants to say that it's fine to put it in someone else's house.
他人の家に置いてもいいよ、と誰もが言いたいのです。
So it's a controversy
だから論争になってるんだよ
What do you say
あなたは何を言っていますか
that nuclear waste
あの核廃棄物
That's not something that will happen today or in the next year.
それは今日や来年に起こることではありません。
Then we will have been producing in the past few decades.
それから私たちは過去数十年間生産し続けてきました。
Right, then can you continue to store in the existing place
そうですね、それでは引き続き既存の場所に保管できますか
even said to store it in a nuclear power plant
原子力発電所に保管すると言われている
that's what we're already doing now
それは私たちがすでに今やっていることです
Everyone should know
誰もが知っておくべきです
Nuclear abolition just like I said Ptonium is one of them
先ほど言ったように核廃絶、プトニウムもその一つです
it is still active
まだ活動中です
OK so you're not saying just throw it in a pile
OK、だからただ山に投げ込むと言っているわけではありません
This radioactive element
この放射性元素は
it has a
それは
it will keep releasing this
これをリリースし続けます
These things in Alpha particle's New Chore
アルファ粒子の新しい仕事のこれらのこと
But most importantly things like nuclear bombs
しかし最も重要なことは核爆弾のようなものです
It has one of the most important principles
それには最も重要な原則の 1 つがあります
called a chain reaction
連鎖反応と呼ばれる
Chain reaction is called Chain reaction
連鎖反応をチェインリアクションと言います
it means me
それは私を意味します
It is OK to put the color temperature and temperature here
ここに色温度と温度を入れてもOKです
It's OK to put this here
ここに入れても大丈夫ですよ
But it's not OK when you put the two together
でもこの2つを一緒にするとダメだよ
because it keeps pointing out
指摘し続けるから
it keeps pointing out
それは指摘し続ける
when you put it close
近くに置くと
its middle finger hits it
中指が当たる
it just exploded
それはちょうど爆発した
So you can't put a lot of lung ingredients together
つまり、肺の成分をたくさん組み合わせることができない
The Japanese one is more special
日本のものはもっと特別です
That is, it has a certain amount of cooling
つまり、ある程度の冷却効果があります
As a result, an earthquake suddenly interrupted the cooling water
その結果、地震により冷却水が突然遮断された
that's information
それは情報です
good
良い
our lung material
私たちの肺の物質
the first has nowhere to go
一人目は行くところがない
the second
二番目
where our nuclear power plant can be placed
原子力発電所が設置できる場所
almost full
ほぼいっぱい
OK
OK
So now as far as I know
それで今、私が知っている限りでは
Taipower is even considering saying
タイパワーはこう言うことも検討している
we are in winter this
私たちは今年冬にいます
When energy demand is not so high
エネルギー需要がそれほど高くないとき
we deload the nuclear power plant
私たちは原子力発電所の荷を降ろします
so not so much river waste
川のゴミはそれほど多くない
Then turn it up a bit more when needed
必要に応じてもう少し上げます
It's because there's no place for river waste
川のゴミを捨てる場所がないからです
Then you say that you can build a few more houses nearby to do it.
それからあなたは、近くに家をもう数軒建てればそれができると言いました。
then they have what's called dry storage
それから乾式保管庫と呼ばれるものがあります
Now we're talking about wet storage
ここで湿った保管について話します
Put this river waste in some kind of water
この川の廃棄物をある種の水に入れてください
You said dry storage exists?
ドライストレージが存在すると言いましたか？
We were going to open
オープンするつもりだった
Is it approved by the Taipei County Government?
台北県政府によって承認されていますか?
The Taipei County Government will never issue licenses
台北県政府は決して免許を発行しない
Then you have to do it when you have a motor
モーターがあるときにそれを行う必要があります
You can't do it with the budget
予算的には無理だよね
Guanghe waste is enough of a headache
広河の廃棄物だけでも十分頭の痛い問題だ
As for whether it is possible to happen like Che Nuobao
チェ・ヌオバオのようなことが起こり得るかどうかについては
like the tutoring question
家庭教師の質問のように
That's a question of risk
それはリスクの問題です
Last time we said there was a risk, that's okay.
前回、リスクがあると言いましたが、大丈夫です。
It's a risk for me to drive
私にとって運転するのは危険です
It's also risky for me to fly.
私にとって飛行機に乗るのも危険です。
It's also a risk for me to take the high-speed rail.
高速鉄道に乗るのも危険です。
risk you buy insurance
リスクを冒して保険を購入する
is there anyone today
今日は誰かいますか
Is there any men's insurance company that sells it?
販売している男性保険会社はありますか？
nuclear disaster insurance for you
あなたのための原子力災害保険
Is it sure to make money?
確実に儲かりますか？
Everyone is scared, right?
みんな怖いですよね？
The insurance company must make money
保険会社は儲けなければならない
but i tell you
でも私はあなたに言います
If he can sell nuclear disaster insurance today
今すぐ原子力災害保険を販売できれば
he absolutely lied to you
彼は絶対にあなたに嘘をつきました
Because in the event of a nuclear disaster
原発事故が起きたら
he can't afford it
彼にはそれを買う余裕がない
right
右
So many things are unresolved
多くのことが未解決です
so
それで
that's all i can say
私が言えるのはそれだけです
that political issue
その政治問題
This is very oriented
これは非常に指向性が高い
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
over there please
あそこにお願いします
should use that mic
そのマイクを使うべきです
is a very
とても
It's a source of energy worth using.
利用する価値のあるエネルギー源です。
yes
はい
But I've heard people say that I don't know
しかし、人々が私は知らないと言っているのを聞いたことがあります
right or wrong
正しいか間違っているか
He said he still wants yours
彼はまだあなたのものが欲しいと言った
board
ボード
Then he still has his time
それなら彼にはまだ時間がある
his deadline
彼の締め切り
take him there
彼をそこに連れて行って
thank you
ありがとう
solar general
太陽一般
because he is using
彼が使っているから
For example C, silicon
例えばC、シリコン
He has a lot of material on one surface
彼は片面にたくさんの素材を持っています
Elements
要素
Then if after using
そして、使用後であれば
direct reuse
直接再利用
or just let it go back to
または単に元に戻してください
There is actually not much pollution on the surface
実際には表面にはそれほど汚染はありません
fine solar energy for people to combine
人々が組み合わせることができる優れた太陽エネルギー
all solar alike
すべての太陽光発電は同様に
You said I made this solar energy
あなたは、この太陽エネルギーは私が作ったと言った
The efficiency is very high and the cost will be paid back in a few years
効率が非常に高く、コストは数年で回収できる
but someone said
でも誰かが言いました
No, if you count
いや、数えてみれば
you come out of the surface
あなたは地面から出てくる
And then store it until the end this solar energy
そしてこの太陽エネルギーを最後まで蓄えておこう
that cost
その費用
the phone you speak
あなたが話す電話
It is also very likely to be ignored by you
無視される可能性も非常に高いです
He said no, but when he sold me
彼はノーと言った、しかし彼が私を売ったとき
Those costs are factored in
それらのコストは織り込まれています
he said no
彼はノーと言った
because we are all
なぜなら今は私たち全員が
especially in taiwan
特に台湾では
Our store is built to sell
私たちの店は販売するために作られています
store or gasoline
店かガソリン
We don't have a detective now
今は探偵がいない
is when you consider an energy source
エネルギー源を考えるとき
you can't talk
あなたは話すことができません
what a job i do when i go with it
それを持って行ったとき、私はどんな仕事をしましたか
you should consider saying
言うことを検討すべきです
when i use it to go
出かけるときに使うとき
I generate that pollution
私はその汚染を生み出します
is there any cost
費用はかかりますか
right
右
It's the same as He Leng
ヘレンと同じだよ
wow some say it's the cheapest energy
すごい、これが最も安いエネルギーだと言う人もいる
but then
しかしその後
If you remove the liquid from the river power plant
河川発電所から液体を取り除く場合
You waste the river from the river power plant
河川発電所から川を無駄にしている
Once counted, it becomes the most expensive
数えたらそれが一番高価になる
so many things to consider
考慮すべきことがたくさんあります
The process of making this solar panel
このソーラーパネルができるまでの過程
Its many unaccounted for costs
多くの未計上コスト
also in it
その中にも
But I guess pollution is not an important
でも汚染は重要ではないと思う
All right
わかった
come here
ここに来て
ask for advice
アドバイスを求める
our land of taiwan
私たちの土地、台湾
not big
大きくない
and then add that
そしてそれを追加します
365 days a year
1年365日
number of days in the sun
太陽に当たる日数
For us in Taiwan
台湾の私たちにとって
like solar panels
ソーラーパネルのような
seems not suitable
好像不太適合
we taiwan
私たち台湾
Sun exposure is of course
日焼けはもちろん
a very important
とても重要な
For example, we are in Taipei
たとえば、私たちは台北にいます
Follow in Kaohsiung
高雄でフォローする
Tainan is different
台南は違う
sunny
日照的
number of days
日数
That
それか
Taiwan does
台湾はそうする
english day
英語的天
than other countries
他の国よりも
come more
もっと来てください
mean to say
言う意味
your solar panel
あなたのソーラーパネル
to recycle
リサイクルする
I need money to invest
投資するにはお金が必要です
It used to be said that it might take 15 years to recycle
リサイクルには15年かかるとも言われていました
down to the original
オリジナルに至るまで
a fifth of the price
価格の5分の1
Can be recycled in five years
5年でリサイクル可能
that's good
それは良い
then if you
もしあなたが
you put it on a
あなたはそれを上に置きます
A place where there is not much sunlight
あまり日の当たらない場所
That might take ten years to recycle
リサイクルするには10年かかるかもしれない
So it's all a consideration
だからそれはすべて考慮事項です
but
しかし
If we put these facilities
こういう設備を置けば
We are contracted to a company
私たちは企業と契約しています
It will definitely do the actuarial calculation of the cost
費用の数理計算は間違いなく行われます
For example, wind power
例えば風力発電
no one would have dared
誰もあえてしなかっただろう
right
右
wow you want to say
うわ、言いたいの？
this wind power
この風力発電
One set up
1つのセットアップ
Hundreds of millions in one sitting
一度に何億も
right
右
then you start talking
それからあなたは話し始めます
How soon can I recycle, right?
どれくらいでリサイクルできるでしょうか？
What about especially
特にどうですか
the government is pushing
政府が推進している
Because you are taking pictures of this windmill on the road
道路にあるこの風車の写真を撮っているからです。
Still have to fight a lot
まだまだたくさん戦わなければならない
So what our government is doing now is
それで、私たちの政府が今やっていることは、
ok then i'll go offshore
わかった、じゃあ沖に行くよ
do it on the sea
海でやれよ
Then do it on the sea
じゃあ海でやれよ
that cost maybe three times
おそらく3倍の費用がかかる
especially Taiwan
特に台湾
past
過去
Without this deep sea construction and these technologies
この深海建設とこれらの技術がなければ
But you go and see
でもあなたは行って見てください
If you drive from the highway
高速道路から車で行く場合
When it's time to stop and say
立ち止まって言う時が来たら
Hey, there are many windmills over there
ほら、あそこに風車がたくさんあるよ
But there are two windmills in the sea
でも海には風車が二つある
And those two windmills are
そして、その2つの風車は、
A company in Taiwan called Shango
Shangoという台湾の会社
to put it up
それを載せる
OK, originally, before that
OK、もともとその前に
Many foreign companies are afraid to enter
多くの外資系企業は参入を恐れている
That is, is this possible?
つまり、それは可能ですか？
There is a typhoon in Taiwan, what is it?
台湾に台風が来ていますが、何ですか？
Uedo spent a lot of money, the cost of learning
小野さんはたくさんのお金、学習費を費やしました
After building those two windmills together
二つの風車を一緒に建てた後
Now everyone including Denmark, including Germany, Siemens has come in
現在、デンマーク、ドイツ、シーメンスを含むすべての企業が参入しています。
Everyone Comes to Bid for Taiwan's Wind Power
台湾の風力発電に誰もが入札に来る
So, this thing is basically a cost
つまり、これは基本的にコストです
It's the same with solar
太陽光発電も同じです
If the sun is strong and you have a lot of sunshine
日差しが強くて日差しが多い場合
Of course your cost will be reduced
もちろんコストも削減されます
but
しかし
Don't worry too much, let those companies decide whether he has to come or not
あまり心配しないでください、彼が来なければならないかどうかはそれらの会社に決めてもらいましょう
If someone is willing to invest, it is obviously worth it
誰かが投資する気があるなら、それは明らかに価値がある
Of course, apart from sunlight, your unit price, the unit price of solar panels has been falling
もちろん、太陽光とは別に、太陽光パネルの単価も下がってきています。
Then again, all your government measures, and how long you have been ordered, actually have a relationship, okay?
繰り返しになりますが、政府のすべての措置と、どのくらいの期間命令を受けているかが実際には重要です。
Can you use the microphone, others can't hear it, press it, press the green one
マイクを使ってもらえますか。他の人には聞こえません。マイクを押してください。緑色のマイクを押してください。
OK, thank you, then the things we usually recycle, paper, can be recycled, right?
はい、ありがとうございます。では、私たちが普段リサイクルしている紙、つまり紙もリサイクルできるのですね。
Scrap iron can be recycled, which solar panels can be recycled, can it be
鉄くずはリサイクルできる、ソーラーパネルもリサイクルできる、できるだろうか
I heard it's not possible
それは不可能だと聞きました
Everything can be recycled, but after you recycle
あらゆるものはリサイクルできますが、リサイクルした後は
what are you doing
あなたは何をしている
For example, you said that our previous
たとえば、以前の
We call it Pai Tan Gu Xia, that canned food, what?
私たちはそれをパイタングシア、缶詰食品と呼んでいますが、何ですか？
Even the glass is recycled
ガラスもリサイクルされる
It's good to recycle and use
リサイクルして使うのもいいですね
but for a while
しかししばらくの間
The recycling price is not high
リサイクル価格は高くない
hospital is low
病院は少ない
That is to say, have you reused it after recycling?
つまり、リサイクルして再利用していますか？
to what extent
どの程度まで
That thing is actually worth it
あれは実際にそれだけの価値がある
we went to develop
私たちは開発に行きました
That is, you will see game companies
つまり、ゲーム会社が表示されます
He specializes in recycling
彼はリサイクルを専門としています
Then if he succeeds, you will find out that
それで彼が成功したら、次のことがわかるだろう
Wow, he can really turn trash into gold
うわー、彼は本当にゴミを金に変えることができるんだ
Wow, we admire that very much
わあ、とても感心します
because he did you know that
なぜなら彼はあなたがそれを知っていたからです
The best country in the world
世界で最高の国
called Taiwan
台湾と呼ばれる
ok then do you know why
わかりました、それでは理由がわかりますか
Tzu Chi
子チー
Tzu Chi volunteers
慈済ボランティア
especially in rural areas
特に田舎では
it's hard for you to imagine saying
あなたが言うことを想像するのは難しい
you know that
あなたはそれを知っています
Is the political performance law
政治パフォーマンス法ですか
There are a lot of things we don't necessarily agree on
必ずしも同意できないこともたくさんある
the meaning of the word
その言葉の意味
But he once said that
しかし彼はかつてこう言いました
do recycling
リサイクルをする
just doing meritorious deeds
ただ功績のある行為をしているだけ
So many volunteers
こんなにたくさんのボランティアが
while he was doing this
彼がこれをしている間
indeed to the whole society
まさに社会全体にとって
make a great contribution
多大な貢献をする
what do we have to do
やらなければいけないことは何
Some messages continue to say that he bullies the weak
弱い者いじめをしているというメッセージもいくつかある
That means
つまり、
so i say i'm not quite
だから私はまだ完全ではないと言います
agree with everything he does
彼のやることすべてに同意する
but his
しかし彼の
recycle this thing
これをリサイクルしてください
If it wasn't for continuing to bring up
育て続けていなかったら
Taiwan does not have such a good situation
台湾はそこまで良い状況ではない
you know
ほら
I just came back from India two weeks ago
2週間前にインドから帰ってきたばかりです
That
それか
India also has beautiful places
インドにも美しい場所はあります
then you say
それからあなたは言います
a pile of garbage over there a pile of garbage
あそこにゴミの山 ゴミの山
then don't say that
だったらそんなこと言わないで
the last time i went to india
最後にインドに行ったとき
one of my own students
私自身の生徒の一人
read TIGP
TIGPを読む
well done here
ここでよくやった
then to india
それからインドへ
do we just live in a car
私たちはただ車の中で暮らしているだけですか？
after dinner
夕食後
Everyone was eating in the car
みんな車の中で食べてた
I ate six or seven lunch boxes
お弁当を6、7個食べました
to a place
ある場所へ
he just opened the car door
彼はちょうど車のドアを開けたところです
that kind of bento
そんなお弁当
I took a look
見てみました
startled say
驚いて言う
What are you doing
あなたは何をしている
No, everyone is like this
いや、みんなそうなんだよ
that
それか
everyone's eco-friendly
みんな環境に優しい
Consciousness not yet
意識はまだない
does not exist yet
まだ存在しません
That
それか
so
それで
actual contribution
実際の貢献度
in that respect
その観点において
I affirmed to him
私は彼にそう断言した
OK
OK
come please
来てください
professor has a
教授が持っている
Can
できる
I have a question
質問があります
Many Koran soldiers in Taiwan
台湾には多くのコーラン兵士がいる
Then a mining of this Koran soldier
それからこのコーランの兵士の採掘
Are you currently in
現在在籍していますか
Therefore, relevant units are studying
そのため、関連部署が検討を進めています。
This is the first question
これが最初の質問です
The second question is
2番目の質問は、
Magma An underground vault in Yangmingshan
マグマ 陽明山の地下金庫
The magma basement is 70,000 square kilometers
マグマ地下は7万平方キロメートル
so big
とても大きく
it's lava fever
溶岩熱だ
Is there any international institution doing research
研究を行っている国際機関はありますか
Thank you, the geothermal heat is what you said
ありがとう、地熱って君が言ったんだ
Not necessarily lava heat
溶岩熱とは限りません
yes it is
はい、そうです。
good
良い
The first Koran soldiers
最初のコーランの兵士
Kelan soldiers, we call them
ケランの兵士、私たちは彼らをそう呼んでいます
First
甲
A, eh, is it the A bowl? It's not the A bowl
あ、え、A丼ですか?A丼ではありません
Is Kelanbing a bowl?
ケランビンはボウルですか？
It's a bowl, sorry
丼です、ごめんなさい
A bowl
ボウル
Of course it is because in the depths of the sea
もちろん深海ですから
under a certain pressure
一定の圧力の下で
then the presented
それから提示された
These liquid cups
この液体カップは
then we also have someone to go
それなら私たちにも行く人がいます
go
行く
Go get it out and show it to everyone
取り出してみんなに見せてください
That's not it, it's like scooping up sea water
そうじゃない、海水をすくうようなもの
right away, isn't it?
すぐですよね？
Well, you need to find out more carefully
そうですね、もっと注意深く調べる必要があります
You have to bring it up from such a deep sea
こんなに深い海から引き上げないといけないのですね
This is a great technical difficulty
これは技術的に大きな困難です
second bowl
2杯目
we will all talk
みんなで話しましょう
if you don't handle it well
うまく対処しないと
Then let part of it go up into the air
次に、その一部を空中に上げます
The impact of Bowl A on global warming
ボウルAの地球温暖化への影響
100 times more than carbon dioxide
二酸化炭素の100倍
It's the one that absorbs infrared rays
赤外線を吸収するやつです
Our name is Cross section, very high
私たちの名前は、断面、非常に高いです
So if it goes into the air
それで、もしそれが空中に出たら
that's another question
それは別の質問です
Let me give you an example
例を挙げてみましょう
i watched a video
ビデオを見ました
Even Japan, they are also interested in studying this armored soldier
日本でもこの装甲兵の研究に興味がある
Of course you can think of Azhi
もちろん、アジのことを考えることもできます
Japanese technology they are in
彼らがいる日本の技術
A lot has been done in all aspects
あらゆる面で多くのことが行われてきました
Japan in order to study this foot bowl ice
このフットボウルアイスを研究するために日本へ
Later found out that doing research at sea
後で、海上で研究をしていることが分かりました。
the cost is too high
コストが高すぎる
then he ran to canada
それから彼はカナダへ走った
Alberta, Canada
アルバータ州、カナダ
on their glacier
彼らの氷河の上で
Drill down on the ground to get a foot bowl of ice
地面をドリルダウンして、フットボウルの氷を入手します
They've been doing research there for ten years
彼らはそこで10年間研究を行っている
OK
OK
That is to say, the research on the foot bowl ice
つまりフットボウルアイスの研究
I have no idea
何も思いつきません
That is to say, take a look and say from the Japanese they
つまり、日本人から見て、彼らはこう言います。
spent ten years
10年を費やした
Stationed in Canada to do research here
研究のためカナダに駐在
today we just say
今日はただ言います
The east coast also has foot bowl ice
東海岸にはフットボウルアイスもあります
They're talking about how little work we've done
彼らは私たちが行った仕事がいかに少ないかについて話しています
far less than others
他の人よりもはるかに少ない
then i didn't answer your question
それから私はあなたの質問に答えませんでした
Is that possible?
それは可能ですか？
But at least what I'm going to say is that
しかし、少なくとも私が言いたいのは、
If you want to use it, you have to pay a considerable price to know it and study it, okay?
それを使いたいなら、それを知り、勉強するためにかなりの代償を払わなければなりませんね？
Then you will secondly refer to the magma in Yangmingshan, they said that I don’t know much about it
次に陽明山のマグマについて言及しますが、私はそれについてあまり知らないと言われました。
Well, if you are hot, there are people going to invest in a certain place in Yilan now
まあ、あなたが熱いなら、今宜蘭の特定の場所に投資しようとしている人がいます
It is to make clear water, and to make a geothermal power generation, which is different from the thermoelectricity I talked about.
きれいな水を作ることと、先ほどの火力発電とは違いますが、地熱発電をすることです。
It draws out the heat to make a traditional generator
熱を取り出して従来の発電機を作る
Now some people are doing that research, so is it possible for Yang Mingshan to be better? I don’t know
今、その研究をしている人もいますが、陽明山のほうが優れているという可能性はありますか?わかりません。
OK, just to ask, there are some companies in Taiwan
OK、ちょっと聞きたいのですが、台湾にいくつかの会社があります。
Lin Jian's company
林建さんの会社
currently in
現在いる
Develop commercial space rockets
商業宇宙ロケットの開発
Currently for space rockets
現在は宇宙ロケット用
development prospects
発展の見通し
Can you analyze it
分析してもらえますか
inside my speech
私のスピーチの中で
Although there is talk of spaceships
宇宙船の話もありますが、
but with the rocket
でもロケットでは
two yards
2ヤード
but as far as i know
しかし、私が知っている限りでは
For example, explain
たとえば、説明します
Explain that there is a professor Wu Zongxin
呉宗信教授がいることを説明する
I know him
私は彼を知っている
Because he's my junior on the infected team
感染チームの後輩だから
National Taiwan University infection team
国立台湾大学感染症チーム
he is the one
彼がその人です
the middle one
真ん中のもの
key person
キーパーソン
why did he do this
なぜ彼はこんなことをしたのか
why did he do research
なぜ彼は研究をしたのか
well done too
もよくやった
why do that
なぜそんなことをするのか
Of course he is important
もちろん彼は大切です
one country
一個國家
is there a way to launch a rocket
ロケットを打ち上げる方法はありますか
space
空
this is a
これは
my country did i land on the moon
私の国、私は月に着陸しましたか？
did i land on mars
私は火星に着陸しましたか
it's a big milestone
それは大きなマイルストーンです
Of course you if the rocket can go up, like North Korea
もちろん、北朝鮮のようにロケットが上昇できるならあなたも
right
右
it went up
上がった
America has to be in awe of its three points
アメリカはその3つのポイントに畏敬の念を抱くべきだ
its nuclear bomb succeeded
核爆弾は成功した
this is amazing
これは素晴らしいです
it's not just nuclear bombs
核爆弾だけではない
its clear bomb
その明らかな爆弾
one is fission
一つは核分裂です
it's nuclear fusion
それは核融合です
That's much more powerful
それははるかに強力です
it proves to you
それはあなたに証明します
so many milestones
とてもたくさんのマイルストーン
then if we have a way
それなら私たちに方法があるなら
successfully launched a rocket into space
宇宙へのロケットの打ち上げに成功した
yes has its importance
はい、重要性があります
That
それか
I don't need to talk about it later, what are you going to do?
後で話す必要はありません、どうするつもりですか？
I will do it for peaceful purposes
平和目的でやるよ
I can't tell
わかりません
I'm doing it for defense
防衛のためにやってる
I don't hit people but if someone hits me
私は人を殴らないけど、もし誰かが私を殴ったら
then i think i will fight back
それなら反撃すると思う
something like
之類的東西
then his story is kind of interesting
それなら彼の話はちょっと面白いですね
Do you know where his funds come from?
彼の資金がどこから来たのか知っていますか?
Jiaotong University
交通大学
Jiaotong University is not a school
交通大学は学校ではありません
That's what they're working on launching rockets
それが彼らがロケットの打ち上げに取り組んでいることです
want money
お金が欲しい
Basically, it's all about national honor.
基本的には国家の名誉がすべてです。
Then he is not
それでは彼はそうではありません
Do you know where his money comes from?
彼のお金がどこから来たのか知っていますか?
Private fundraising, have you ever invested?
個人募金、投資したことありますか？
None of us invested. How did he raise money?
私たちの誰も投資しませんでしたが、彼はどうやって資金を集めたのですか?
there is a taiwanese
台湾人がいる
He went to the Soviet Union very early
彼はとても早い時期にソ連に行った
to do business
ビジネスをする
And then this 1989
そしてこの1989年
the end of the cold war
冷戦の終わり
the collapse of the soviet union
ソ連の崩壊
sell it in the country
国内でも売ってください
He used that agency to buy a bunch of oil fields
彼はその代理店を利用して油田を大量に購入した
now he has a lot of oil fields now
今では彼にはたくさんの油田があります
Of course the oil fields are producing oil all the time.
もちろん、油田では常に石油が生産されています。
So when he came back a little bit, he talked to a few people
それで彼は少し戻ってきたとき、何人かと話しました
Taiwan needs rockets
台湾にはロケットが必要だ
Then I'll give you 100 million
じゃあ1億あげるよ
you go away with one million
あなたは100万を持って行きます
Then my student is like this
そしたらうちの生徒はこんな感じです
One day the boss said
ある日上司がこう言いました
I give you two benzes
ベンツを2台あげます
Then you have one
それなら、あなたはそれを持っています
Then start asking money every year to do it
そして、それを行うために毎年お金を要求し始めます
I admire it very much
とても感心します
that means he is meaningful
つまり彼には意味があるということだ
Aren't they like box bombs, right?
箱爆弾みたいなものじゃないですか？
Box bombs are not always head-on
箱爆弾は常に正面を向いているわけではありません
but the rocket
でもロケットは
I remember needing
必要だったのを覚えています
we should have some dreams
私たちはいくつかの夢を持つべきです
good
良い
I think it's time to stop here
ここでやめるべき時が来たと思う
Is there a problem with the network
ネットワークに問題がありますか
maybe no one is watching
たぶん誰も見てない
right
右
no problem
問題ない
yes
はい
Did you prepare it yourself?
自分で用意したんですか？
good
良い
Internet says
インターネットは言う
BMW installs thermoelectric system on balloon
BMW、気球に熱電システムを設置
car car
車 車
He said that the electricity of these thermoelectric systems
彼は、これらの熱電システムの電気は、
Save them all and when there is enough electricity
全部保存して、電力が十分になったら
Just start the motor and that's it
モーターを始動するだけで完了です
It's like making a kind of thermoelectric
一種の熱電素子を作るようなものです
Hybrid system
ハイブリッドシステム
Is this better than the current one?
これは現行のものより優れていますか?
The Hybrid system is more cost-effective, which probably means this
ハイブリッド システムはコスト効率が高いため、おそらくこれが意味します。
then i think
それから私は思います
He talks about BMW
彼はBMWについて話します
Since the ranking is very high, I just talked about 70% of the
ランキングが非常に高いので7割程度お話しました。
It's all waste heat, you even need a cooler
すべて廃熱なのでクーラーも必要です
This water tank is to cool it, then you said there is a way to put it
この水槽は冷やすためのものだ、だったら置く方法があるって言ってたね
part of the recycling, but currently
リサイクルの一環ですが、現在は
About 5% can be recycled
約5%がリサイクル可能
Then you become electricity, the 5% electricity is of course
そうすればあなたは電気になります、5%の電気はもちろんです
It's better to make up less
メイクは減らしたほうがいいよ
You charge it, fill up your electrons
あなたはそれを充電し、あなたの電子を満たしてください
Or it's good for other purposes
あるいは他の目的にも良い
The only problem right now is
今のところ唯一の問題は
The material itself is too expensive
材料自体が高すぎる
how do we find
どうやって見つけますか
The element that is more abundant on the surface
表面に多く含まれる元素
Then reduce the cost if the key player is like this
じゃあキープレイヤーがこうならコストを下げる
I think everyone is deeply concerned about this today.
今日は誰もがこのことを深く懸念していると思います。
Realize that this energy costs money
このエネルギーにはお金がかかることを理解してください
Energy saving also costs money
省エネにもお金がかかる
So I
それで私は
follow today's talk, I want to help our dean
今日の話を聞いてください、私たちの学部長を助けたいです
This Saturday, last Saturday
今週の土曜日、先週の土曜日
He made a very important point, that is,
彼は非常に重要な点を指摘しました。
To save the global warming crisis
地球温暖化の危機を救うために
There is one very important addition to all these studies
これらすべての研究に非常に重要な追加点が 1 つあります
Everyone needs to adjust mentally
誰もが精神的に調整する必要がある
That means we have to slightly modify the
つまり、少し変更する必要があります
pattern of our lives
私たちの生活パターン
Like he gave a few examples
彼がいくつか例を挙げたように
it's very simple
それはとても簡単です
Do you want to turn it up one degree
1度上げますか?
Do you want to think more about building a large and medium transportation system when you go out?
外出時の大中型交通システムの構築についてもっと考えてみませんか？
And eat more vegetables and fruits and less meat
そして肉を減らして野菜や果物をもっと食べましょう
Especially the beef he choked
特に彼が窒息させた牛肉
Don't underestimate this
これを過小評価しないでください
Because if more people do
なぜなら、もっと多くの人がそうすれば、
Then his consumption of the whole energy
それから彼の全エネルギーの消費
Of course it will help a lot
もちろんとても役に立ちますよ
So it's pretty comprehensive
したがって、かなり包括的です
I am also very touched today
今日もとても感動しました
That is to say, everyone is so concerned about energy issues.
つまり、誰もがエネルギー問題に非常に関心を持っているということです。
But from Mr. Chen's speech just now, we also know that
しかし、今の陳氏のスピーチから、私たちは次のことも知っています。
He is actually a very complex
実は彼はとてもコンプレックスが強い人です
It's not that a new technology is necessarily better
新しいテクノロジーが必ずしも優れているというわけではない
Must be because the new technology is more expensive
新しい技術は高価だからに違いない
That's not something any technology can solve.
それはどんなテクノロジーでも解決できるものではありません。
He is actually a very comprehensive question
彼は実際には非常に包括的な質問です
There are many young students here
ここには若い学生がたくさんいます
This looks like a lot of potential
これはかなりの可能性を秘めているように見えます
We hope that we can also invest in research in this area
この分野の研究にも投資できることを願っています
Our Chinese language also has many teams doing research in this area
私たちの中国語にも、この分野で研究を行っている多くのチームがあります
But he needs long-term hard work
しかし彼には長期にわたる努力が必要だ
Okay then again we take this opportunity to thank speaker Yan
それでは、この機会にヤン講演者に改めて感謝いたします。
Thank you all for participating
ご参加いただきました皆様、ありがとうございました
Thanks
ありがとう
Then our next game is this
それでは次のゲームはこれです
The next feast of knowledge will be on November 27
次回の知識の饗宴は11月27日です
There is another theme we find
私たちが見つけたもう一つのテーマがあります
Shock-absorbing roof
分身所減震頂
Special researchers also talk about this nerve
特別研究員もこの神経について語る
Then I think interested guests can
そうすれば、興味のあるゲストはできると思います
Or you know someone who is interested and can help us spread the word
または、興味があり、情報を広めるのに協力してくれる人を知っていますか
November 27 Thank you all thank you
11月27日 みなさん、ありがとう、ありがとう
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました